<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Laos on Matt Burns</title>
    <link>https://mattburns.github.io/categories/laos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Laos on Matt Burns</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 10:09:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mattburns.github.io/categories/laos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 170 – Wednesday 2nd March – Don Det &amp; Don Khon (Si Phan Don – 4000 islands)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/04/03/day-170-wednesday-2nd-march-don-det-don-khon-si-phan-don-4000-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 10:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/04/03/day-170-wednesday-2nd-march-don-det-don-khon-si-phan-don-4000-islands/</guid>
      <description>An hour and half longtail down the Mekong brought us to the island of Don Det. It’s the 4000 island’s answer to Vang Vieng as Don Khong is to Luang Prabang. Although both are on a much smaller scale there were the usual bedraggled hungover backpackers in their tubing vests, saggy hotpants and cigarettes hanging out their mouths loitering.
Can’t complain too much. Although our bungalow is basic and has a shared bathroom I am getting up-to-date with the blogs whilst lying in a hammock on the balcony with 180 degree views of the Mekong and across to Cambodia, and Matt’s snoozing in the hammock next to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 168 &amp; 169 – Monday 28th February to Tuesday 1st March – Don Khong (Si Phan Don – 4000 islands)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/04/03/day-168-169-monday-28th-february-to-tuesday-1st-march-don-khong-si-phan-don-4000-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 10:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/04/03/day-168-169-monday-28th-february-to-tuesday-1st-march-don-khong-si-phan-don-4000-islands/</guid>
      <description>Is it really March already? Unbelievable. Where does the time go when you’re having fun travelling around Asia?
Monday’s journey consisted of a 20min long boat from the bottom of the garden of Souchitra guest house (opposite our guest house) across the Mekong to Ban Muang, then a minivan for 90 mins down to Hat Xai Kun, followed by a 10min small longtail back across the Mekong to Muang Khong on Don Khong island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 166 &amp; 167 – Saturday 26th to Sunday 27th February – Champasak – Wat Phu Champasak</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/04/03/day-166-167-saturday-26th-to-sunday-27th-february-champasak-wat-phu-champasak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 10:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/04/03/day-166-167-saturday-26th-to-sunday-27th-february-champasak-wat-phu-champasak/</guid>
      <description>After a nice lie-in, the first in a while, a good banana pancake for brekkie from the local Indian, also a first in a while, and an excellent cup of coffee we jumped in a “remork-moto” to the new market (Talat Dao Heung) bus station. There have been many different designs of tuk-tuk in Lao and this was our first sat aside a motorbike in a 2 person carriage that looks like it might from a ferris wheel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 164 &amp; 165 – Thursday 24th to Friday 25th February – Green Discovery Tree Top Explorer 2 day trek</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/05/day-164-165-thursday-24th-to-friday-25th-february-green-discovery-tree-top-explorer-2-day-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 14:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/05/day-164-165-thursday-24th-to-friday-25th-february-green-discovery-tree-top-explorer-2-day-trek/</guid>
      <description>Don’t know where to begin with the last two days. Out of this world is one way to describe them.
Tree Top Explorer is a new venture run by Green Discovery that has only been running 2 months.
Our trek begins 90mins outside of Pakse at a village south of Paksong in the heart of the Bolaven Plateau famous for its coffee. We stop at a house with a woman roasting coffee beans in a wok over a low fire and where thousands of coffee beans are drying in the backyard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 163 – Wednesday 23rd February – Tha Khaek to Pakse</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/05/day-163-wednesday-23rd-february-tha-khaek-to-pakse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 14:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/05/day-163-wednesday-23rd-february-tha-khaek-to-pakse/</guid>
      <description>Got our backsides in order today and got out of bed and to the bus station in time for the 9am local bus to Pakse. This was the busiest bus we’ve been on so far in Laos. Only 1 mile after starting out there were more people than seats so the plastic stools once again came out and by the time we arrived in Pakse 5 hours later the aisle was full of people sitting on stools (or the floor and leaning on stools trying to sleep) with at least 4 people standing at the front.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 161 &amp; 162 – Monday 21st to Tuesday 22nd February – Savannakhet – Eco-guide Unit homestay &amp; trek</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-161-162-monday-21st-to-tuesday-22nd-february-savannakhet-eco-guide-unit-homestay-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 06:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-161-162-monday-21st-to-tuesday-22nd-february-savannakhet-eco-guide-unit-homestay-trek/</guid>
      <description>It’s now 16:30 on Tuesday and just got back from a 2 day spiritual trek around the local area with a night in a homestay at a local village.
It started at a salt factory about 18km from Savannakhet. The Japanese had drilled for oil and instead found salt water which is pumped out of the ground and either dried in the sun for 2 to 3 days or boiled in big vats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 160 – Sunday 20th February – Tha Khaek to Savannakhet</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-160-sunday-20th-february-tha-khaek-to-savannakhet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 06:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-160-sunday-20th-february-tha-khaek-to-savannakhet/</guid>
      <description>Our bus journey from Tha Khaek was quite an interesting one. They played an array of cheesy music videos. Some young kids prancing around. And one old guy. Well say in his late 50s, singing four or five different songs that all sounded the same and for each video he was wearing a shirt and tie and was either stood at the side of a main road with the limestone cliffs in the background or in a field dancing like your dad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 158 to 159 – Friday 18th to Saturday 19th February – Tha Khaek</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-158-to-159-friday-18th-to-saturday-19th-february-tha-khaek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 05:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-158-to-159-friday-18th-to-saturday-19th-february-tha-khaek/</guid>
      <description>Tha Khaek is a funny one. There’s not much here but every guesthouse was full on Friday evening. After trying 4 different guesthouses we ended up in the dodgy Khammouane Inter Guest House next door to the Karaoke, with a single bed masquerading as a double bed. I use the word bed in the loosest of terms as the mattress was rock hard and sunken in the middle. There were no curtains on the rails and the wooden shutters were covered by torn mossie nets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 157 – Thursday 17th February – Vientiane – Admin day</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-157-thursday-17th-february-vientiane-admin-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 05:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-157-thursday-17th-february-vientiane-admin-day/</guid>
      <description>Had a very constructive day doing admin type stuff.
Picked up our passports from the Immigration office and we are now permitted to stay in Laos until 10th March.
Arranged a way of leaving Vientiane (bus to Tha Khaek tomorrow). As lovely as it is 5 nights is enough when there is so much more of Laos to see. We have been staying at Mixay Paradise Guest House so long now that we were eligible for a free coffee and muffin this afternoon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 156 – Wednesday 16th February – Vientiane – Pha That Luang, COPE centre, bowling &amp; Matt gets a haircut</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-156-wednesday-16th-february-vientiane-pha-that-luang-cope-centre-bowling-matt-gets-a-haircut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 05:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-156-wednesday-16th-february-vientiane-pha-that-luang-cope-centre-bowling-matt-gets-a-haircut/</guid>
      <description>Hired bikes from the Youth Inn. Very Parisian with their little wicker baskets on the front.
Went back to the Immigration Office to renew our passports. It takes 24hours so we’re in Vientiane for a couple more days.
Most temples and museums are shut between 12:00 &amp;amp; 13:00 so we sat under the Patuxai (Arc de Triomphe) with a beer &amp;amp; a water to shade from the midday sun. Monday &amp;amp; Tuesday were overcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 154 to 155 – Monday 14th to Tuesday 15th February – Vientiane</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-154-to-155-monday-14th-to-tuesday-15th-february-vientiane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 05:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/03/04/day-154-to-155-monday-14th-to-tuesday-15th-february-vientiane/</guid>
      <description>Had a lovely Valentine’s Day in Vientiane. Moved hotels next door to Mixay Paradise Guest House so now we have a cleaner, more modern room with big windows and views over the temple and brekkie included (heart shaped fried-eggs, toast and curry). Although today’s wasn’t too bad as I had American style pancakes with crispy bacon which I thought I was putting maple syrup on but turned out it to be soya sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 153 – Sunday 13th February 2011 – Vientiane capital of Laos</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-153-sunday-13th-february-2011-vientiane-capital-of-laos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-153-sunday-13th-february-2011-vientiane-capital-of-laos/</guid>
      <description>Thought for the day
It’s 6pm on Sunday evening and I am sat at the Vista wifi cafe in Vientiane surrounded by laptops. Virtually every table is staring at one (me included) even whilst eating dinner there are people leaning across their plates typing away. They’re not sat alone either. (I currently am. Matt is off wandering for an hour as it’s our anniversary tomorrow so he’s doing some shopping I assume).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 152 – Saturday 12th February – Vang Vieng – more tubing the sensible way</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-152-saturday-12th-february-vang-vieng-more-tubing-the-sensible-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-152-saturday-12th-february-vang-vieng-more-tubing-the-sensible-way/</guid>
      <description>Happy birthday Dulcie!
Decided to go tubing again today and our mission was to go all the way down the river back to Vang Vieng before 6pm. We started out at 10:30 and met a couple from Holland called Edo and Annalies in the tuk-tuk there who had done trans-mongolian, china, thailand, cambodia, now laos and onto myanmar and thailand. We arranged to meet for a drink later so they could give us their Cambodia book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 148 to 151 – Tuesday 8th to Friday 11th February – Vang Vieng – Week 2 EEFA English teaching</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-148-to-151-tuesday-8th-to-friday-11th-february-vang-vieng-week-2-eefa-english-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-148-to-151-tuesday-8th-to-friday-11th-february-vang-vieng-week-2-eefa-english-teaching/</guid>
      <description>Happy 30th Birthday Lisa &amp;amp; Happy Birthday Leah!
Tuesday
Back to teaching yesterday and today was jam-packed. Had the same class at the primary school again. This time Mikael another volunteer came and helped me.
Tuesday evening I taught Level 1-1 again on my own this time. Which was fine for a while but soon became rowdy. I played a running game with them where they had to draw pictures on the board and write the word I was saying like Cat, Hat, Fan, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 147 – Monday 7th February – Vang Vieng – Karen’s 33rd birthday</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-147-monday-7th-february-vang-vieng-karens-33rd-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-147-monday-7th-february-vang-vieng-karens-33rd-birthday/</guid>
      <description>It’s my birthday and my nan’s. Happy Birthday Nan!!
Early brekkie at the most basic cafe you can imagine with a lovely little family running it. We’d been here a couple of times before as the views are fantastic. The little girl is so cute. She can hardly be 1 year old and likes teetering around in her mum’s high heels.Hired the same moped again for 5 days. I am becoming a pro now :) And headed off to the farm for the 9am meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 144 to 146 – Friday 4th to Sunday 6th February – Vang Vieng – Karen’s birthday weekend – caves &amp; tubing</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-144-to-146-friday-4th-to-sunday-6th-february-vang-vieng-karens-birthday-weekend-caves-tubing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-144-to-146-friday-4th-to-sunday-6th-february-vang-vieng-karens-birthday-weekend-caves-tubing/</guid>
      <description>Today changed our opinion of Vang Vieng. We saw a different side to it.
No teaching so we had the whole day to ourselves. After a good-lie in and a chilled out brekkie lounging on raised platforms overlooking the Nam Song river and the karsts beyond, we took the moped for a drive across the countryside. And I mean across it. There aren’t many roads the other side of the river and to get to many of the “sightseeing” places such as caves and viewpoints you need to go across farmland, dodging chickens and cows and rocks and streams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 140 to 143 – Monday 31st January to Thursday 4th February – Vang Vieng – Week 1 EEFA English Teaching through the Organic Farm</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-140-to-143-monday-31st-january-to-thursday-4th-february-vang-vieng-week-1-eefa-english-teaching-through-the-organic-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-140-to-143-monday-31st-january-to-thursday-4th-february-vang-vieng-week-1-eefa-english-teaching-through-the-organic-farm/</guid>
      <description>Before heading to Laos I contacted the EEFA Project. EEFA stands for Equal Education For All and is based at the Organic Farm 4km from Vang Vieng in Phoudindeng. I signed up for 2 weeks of volunteering as an English teacher. A chance to use the TEFL skills and to give something back.
Monday morning I was scared to death. I had no real experience of teaching or of working with kids whatsover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 138 to 139 – Saturday 29th to Sunday 30th January – Vang Vieng – initial impressions</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-138-to-139-saturday-29th-to-sunday-30th-january-vang-vieng-initial-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/20/day-138-to-139-saturday-29th-to-sunday-30th-january-vang-vieng-initial-impressions/</guid>
      <description>Vang Vieng is a 7.5 hour bus journey from LP. We were told we were buying a ticket for the 6 hour special VIP trip. They forgot to mention that when the 8am and 9am bus was already full, the 9:30am bus was in fact a less expensive VIP trip with no loo and dismal aircon that took longer but were happy to charge us the same price. If anyone else in Luang Prabang is going to Vang Vieng the ticket at the bus station costs only 90,000 kip for the 9:30 trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 133 to 137 cont… Luang Prabang – Phousi hill, Kop Noi, UXO Lao &amp; sunsets</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/18/day-133-to-137-cont-luang-prabang-phousi-hill-kop-noi-uxo-lao-sunsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 04:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/18/day-133-to-137-cont-luang-prabang-phousi-hill-kop-noi-uxo-lao-sunsets/</guid>
      <description>Whilst I spent my mornings at Big Brother Mouse, Matt concentrated on stolencamerafinder (check it out!). We almost fell into a normal routine. We’d both be up before 8am, ready to go get a breakfast baguette &amp;amp; a strong Lao coffee or Jasmine tea from the local Lao ladies. Matt would have chicken and I would go for Lao-style which is tofu, omelette and some brown hairy stuff.
Then we’d part ways and I’d go on my 10 min walk through the town or the morning market to Big Brother Mouse and Matt would go back to the guest house and get coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Anniversary Matt!</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/14/happy-anniversary-matt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 04:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/14/happy-anniversary-matt/</guid>
      <description>As well as being Valentine’s Day today it is 6 years today since our “non-date” in Wagamamas in Bristol when we hoped no-one we knew would pass the window and spot us just being 2 “friends” out for a meal on what just happened to be Valentine’s Day.
Since then I’ve had the most amazing years ever. And I’m so glad that Matt was up for the same mad plan of giving up everything and going travelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 133 to 137 – Monday 24th to Friday 28th January – Luang Prabang – volunteering at Big Brother Mouse</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-133-to-137-monday-24th-to-friday-28th-january-luang-prabang-volunteering-at-big-brother-mouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 12:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-133-to-137-monday-24th-to-friday-28th-january-luang-prabang-volunteering-at-big-brother-mouse/</guid>
      <description>After 7 days in Luang Prabang we are still not ready to leave. This has to be one of our favourite places of the trip for easy living. It is a beautiful place and the people are so friendly.
I have been volunteering at Big Brother Mouse, a local charity which creates books for kids in Lao and English. They encourage tourists to buy books from their shop or from the market to give to kids who live in villages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 132 – Sunday 23rd January – Luang Prabang</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-132-sunday-23rd-january-luang-prabang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 10:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-132-sunday-23rd-january-luang-prabang/</guid>
      <description>Moved guest house again as although the bed was extra comfy the plumbing had a dodgy odour and there seemed to be a loud woman banging on the doors at all hours. We are far too old for such nonsense. And we were glad to check out as the guy on the desk tried to charge us $15 instead of the 100,000 kip we were quoted. Very rude. Later happened to come across it on Tripadvisor and it was something like #76 our of #98 B&amp;amp;Bs in Luang Prabang and most of the reviews were terrible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 131 – Saturday 22nd January – Pak Beng to Luang Prabang (day 2 of the slow boat down the Mekong river)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-131-saturday-22nd-january-pak-beng-to-luang-prabang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 10:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-131-saturday-22nd-january-pak-beng-to-luang-prabang/</guid>
      <description>Another earlyish start. After yesterday’s overflowing boat we wanted to make sure we got a seat. We boarded the boat at 8:10 for a 9:00 departure to find it was a different boat from yesterday. This time there were about 20 car seats and the rest were stiff wooden benches about 8cm deep.
At least we had a seat though. And there were cushions too covered in teddy bear material and many people didn’t get a seat so can’t complain (much).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 130 – Friday 21st January – Huay Xai to Pak Beng (day 1 of the slow boat down the Mekong River)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-130-friday-21st-january-huay-xai-to-pak-beng-day-1-of-the-slow-boat-down-the-mekong-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 09:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-130-friday-21st-january-huay-xai-to-pak-beng-day-1-of-the-slow-boat-down-the-mekong-river/</guid>
      <description>Not sure what to write about today. It gave us doubts about travelling. Made us feel old. Well me anyway. And like we’d missed the boat (excuse the pun). Yep we have spent all day on a boat full of young twenty-something travellers.
Got up early so we could have breakfast at 8am in time for the boat pickup at 8.30. Pickup then wasn’t til 9.10. Fine OK no problem. Dropped off at the harbourside with our ticket &amp;amp; boat no.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 129 – Thursday 20th January – Thailand to Laos</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-129-thursday-20th-january-thailand-to-laos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 09:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.github.io/travels/2011/02/13/day-129-thursday-20th-january-thailand-to-laos/</guid>
      <description>After exactly 1 month in Thailand we are now in Laos.
It was pretty simple. We jumped on a rickety old bus from Chiang Rai, our bags piled high at the back of the bus with everyone else’s luggage and our knees up under our chins (well Matt’s anyway) and 2.5 hours later we were dropped off at a tuk-tuk stand in Chiang Khong on the border with Laos. 5 min tuk-tuk ride and we were at the Mekong River and border crossing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
