<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Matt Burns</title>
    <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Matt Burns</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 12:28:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mattburns.co.uk/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Domains affected by Enom outage</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2022/01/16/domains-affected-by-enom-outage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2022/01/16/domains-affected-by-enom-outage/</guid>
      <description>Enom has been down for almost 2 days. I thought it might be handy to compile a list of domains known to be affected by the issue. Please let me know if you want yours added to the list&amp;hellip;
 andymassey.com angelakulig.com apsynergy.com argentuniverse.com capitalsigma.biz cetbcn.com christianlady.com christianman.com clarkschool.com coastertouring.com contractsolutions-i.com dancingleaftea.com dellasposa.com frayedpassport.com friday.tv giventorock.com goldentee.tv idealvisaconsultancy.com ilj.com ilovejesus.com imexgf.com kamienskie.info lamberthome.net logansinthecarolinas.com lovemomiji.com lusomerap.com mkuhlmann.com newmyroyals.com oddprints.com oicu812.com productreviewmom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did I find an easter egg in Encanto?</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2022/01/16/did-i-find-an-easter-egg-in-encanto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 20:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2022/01/16/did-i-find-an-easter-egg-in-encanto/</guid>
      <description>At the end of Encanto, I spotted one of the butterfly bricks was placed upside-down
No idea if it means anything, and in a later frame it&amp;rsquo;s the right way up again. Does anyone know why? Yeah, this is a random and boring post. The real reason is I&amp;rsquo;ve just migrated the whole site from wordpress to hugo and I wanted to add a post to test it out&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio on Udemy videos has suddenly stopped working</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2018/02/12/audio-on-udemy-videos-has-suddenly-stopped-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 14:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2018/02/12/audio-on-udemy-videos-has-suddenly-stopped-working/</guid>
      <description>I’m working through a course on Udemy on my macbook with bluetooth headphones. I’ve no idea why but the audio no longer works. Youtube audio is fine, previous lessons no longer have audio either, restarting browser has no effect. Disconnecting headphones makes no difference. Downloading lecture works, but is hassle.
Solution: In bottom-right, click the cog and change the quality from auto to a fixed quality (eg 1080p). This solved it for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cameron hails Stoke Gifford Parish Council as “Most forward-thinking in UK”</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2016/04/13/cameron-hails-stoke-gifford-parish-council-as-most-forward-thinking-in-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 09:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2016/04/13/cameron-hails-stoke-gifford-parish-council-as-most-forward-thinking-in-uk/</guid>
      <description>Stoke Gifford Parish Council voted last night in favour of charging parkrun for use of the local park for members of the public to use for free. The PM has applauded the decision saying that it signifies just the start of some great savings that can be made by government. In a statement last night he said:
 Councils across the country have huge bills for supplying services available for free universally to taxpayers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motorola MBP854 baby monitor</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2016/02/11/motorola-mbp854-baby-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 21:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2016/02/11/motorola-mbp854-baby-monitor/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I’m blogging about a baby monitor.
It’s great, has a massive screen, remotely physically controllable camera, thermometer, streams to my phone when I’m at work, but still works in the house if wifi breaks etc.
However…
Tonight we looked at the screen and thought, gosh, she’s really moving about a lot but not making a peep of sound. We muted the telly so we could hear if she was still breathing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got over £1,200 from HMRC with this one simple trick!</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/07/21/how-i-got-over-1200-from-hmrc-with-this-one-simple-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 13:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/07/21/how-i-got-over-1200-from-hmrc-with-this-one-simple-trick/</guid>
      <description>You won’t believe this hack!
I recently got a cheque for over £1200 from HMRC for “overpaid corporation tax”. Wahoo! Free money!
Unfortunately, as much as I just wanted to cash the cheque and forget about it, I knew there was something wrong. After a bit of rummaging through my records I realised that the amount overpaid was exactly the same as the amount I’ve just paid to HMRC for my latest PAYE bill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to compress a folder of .mov files</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/05/29/how-to-compress-a-folder-of-mov-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 13:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/05/29/how-to-compress-a-folder-of-mov-files/</guid>
      <description>Made a bunch of .movs using quicktime’s screen recording but they’re a bit big? ffmpeg’s default settings when converting to mp4 is a quick win
for i in *.mov; do ffmpeg -i $i $i.mp4; done  Name them alphabetically and you can merge them all together:
ffmpeg -f concat -i &amp;lt;(printf &amp;quot;file &#39;$PWD/%s&#39;\n&amp;quot; ./*.mp4) -c copy merged.mp4  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating a CMYK file for printing</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/05/12/generating-a-cmyk-file-for-printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 13:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/05/12/generating-a-cmyk-file-for-printing/</guid>
      <description>So you want to print something (like a banner) but the printers have asked for it to be int the CMYK colorspace? Well we could argue about how to spell colour or whether CMYK is a colorspace at all. But I can’t be bothered, let’s just cut and paste this command which is what I came up with after a morning of hacking…
convert -resize 9520 -density 300 rgb_input.pdf +profile icm -profile sRGB_IEC61966-2-1_black_scaled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dell U2515H and problems with a USB apple keyboard</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/04/08/dell-u2515h-and-problems-with-a-usb-apple-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 10:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/04/08/dell-u2515h-and-problems-with-a-usb-apple-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE/Short answer: Use the USB extension lead that came with the keyboard! It has better contacts.
Does anyone else ever have problems with this combination? They keyboard just goes dead.
I use the monitor’s USB hub to connect my keyboard and mouse. I then connect the hub to either my macbook or my linux pc and toggle the video inputs. Sometimes the keyboard just dies. When it’s in the broken state the following things are true:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tapiriik not syncing to Dropbox?</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/03/31/how-to-fix-problem-when-tapiriik-not-syncing-dropbox-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 13:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/03/31/how-to-fix-problem-when-tapiriik-not-syncing-dropbox-files/</guid>
      <description>My activities hadn’t been syncing to Dropbox for a while (since mid-November 2014).
 This activity was not synchronized to the following services:
Dropbox: There was a problem indexing your activities on Dropbox, so no activities will be uploaded to Dropbox.
 Everything else was syncing fine (Strava, Endomondo, Garmin).
A quick email to the author and everything is solved:
 If you look in your Dropbox folder there should be a number of files with .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hemington 10k 2013 results</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/03/23/hemington-10k-2013-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 10:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/03/23/hemington-10k-2013-results/</guid>
      <description>Yes, that’s not a typo, these are the results from 2013.
I’m just posting them here because I couldn’t find them on the internet. Managed to find a copy in my email though so thought I’d just post them here in case anyone else is interested:
                Surname First Name Gender Race Category Race Number Finishing Time Position Position within Category Running Club   Ryman Paul M M 157 36.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using an SSL certificate on a custom domain with Google App Engine</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/03/04/using-ssl-certificate-on-a-custom-domain-with-google-app-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 10:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/03/04/using-ssl-certificate-on-a-custom-domain-with-google-app-engine/</guid>
      <description>This post is more a reminder for me. Sorry.
Get an SNI certificate from Gandi. And download the certificate
It will have a name like:
certificate-123456.crt You need to create public and private pem files for google like this:
openssl rsa -in cameraforensics.key -text &amp;gt; private.pem openssl x509 -inform PEM -in certificate-123456.crt &amp;gt; public.pem (cameraforensics.key is my private key from when I created the SSL certificate from Gandi)
In Google Apps domain manager, upload those files under “Security &amp;gt; show more &amp;gt; SSL for custom domains“: I was upgrading my certificate so I see both the current and the new certificate:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garmin forerunner 620 verses the 205. The Good, the Bad and the Ugly</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/01/15/garmin-forerunner-620-verses-the-205-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 23:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2015/01/15/garmin-forerunner-620-verses-the-205-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid>
      <description>I previously had the (very popular) forerunner 205 so this review will be based on comparing it to that. I bought the 205 when it came out in 2006 and it’s still going strong. I love tech though so decided to treat myself to an “upgrade”…
The Good  Wifi and bluetooth data uploading. This is really handy. Saves getting the computer out. The live tracking is also good, but it requires you to take your phone on your run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ugly business practices at Facebook</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/11/05/ugly-business-practices-at-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 10:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/11/05/ugly-business-practices-at-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Facebook have broken its messenger feature into its own app. Lots of people freaked out thinking Facebook wanted to use it to spy on them as it requires excessive permissions etc. In reality, it probably needs all those permissions, I don’t really care about that, privacy died years ago. What bothers me is that people use it instead of emailing me. I strongly prefer email. It’s searchable and owned by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running the 4K AOC U2868PQU and Intel HD4000 graphics…</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/09/30/running-the-4k-aoc-u2868pqu-and-intel-hd4000-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 11:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/09/30/running-the-4k-aoc-u2868pqu-and-intel-hd4000-graphics/</guid>
      <description>Ok, I just bought a 4K display, whoop!
I knew when I bought it that neither my late-2012 Retina Macbook Pro, or my Ubuntu desktop machine would actually drive the monitor at 4K because they both rely on Intel’s HD4000 graphics which is built into their Ivy bridge CPUs. I did however expect to get at least 2560×1440 (if only at 30Hz) which is fine by me, and then I’m ready when I next upgrade…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to download Chromecast background images</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/07/10/how-to-download-chromecast-background-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 11:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/07/10/how-to-download-chromecast-background-images/</guid>
      <description>Google’s friendly little chromecast has some great background images.
If you want to download all of those images so you can have a nice high quality screen saver on your laptop/mobile etc. just do this:
git clone -b patch-1 https://github.com/mattburns/chromecast-backgrounds.git cd chromecast-backgrounds/ npm install lodash q request nopt chalk node cli.js --download=images --size=1024 --load=backgrounds.json  Change the size from 1024 to whatever maximum size you want to download.
I had to tweak the source from this project on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Java 7 on OSX</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/05/16/using-java-7-on-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 10:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/05/16/using-java-7-on-osx/</guid>
      <description>Does your current version point to JDK6 even though you’ve installed JDK7?
matt$ ls -l /System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/CurrentJDK 8 lrwxr-xr-x 1 root wheel 59 21 Nov 14:43 /System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/CurrentJDK -&amp;gt; /System/Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/1.6.0.jdk/Contents The do this:
sudo rm /System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/CurrentJDK sudo ln -s /Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/jdk1.7.0_51.jdk/Contents/ /System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/CurrentJDK If it’s not already, set JAVA_HOME accordingly in your ~/.bash_profile:
export JAVA_HOME=/System/Library/Frameworks/JavaVM.framework/Versions/CurrentJDK/Home Test it worked:
matt$ java -version java version &amp;quot;1.7.0_51&amp;quot; Java(TM) SE Runtime Environment (build 1.7.0_51-b13) Java HotSpot(TM) 64-Bit Server VM (build 24.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a UK mac keyboard on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/04/17/using-a-uk-mac-keyboard-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 17:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/04/17/using-a-uk-mac-keyboard-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>If you’re using a UK edition usb keyboard with Ubuntu, you may be swearing every time you want a relatively common characters like £, # or |.
I’ve been suffering with a poorly mapped keyboard for months. I’ve no idea why, I just assumed I must have tried when I installed the OS and deemed it impossible. Anyway, I’m an idiot because it’s really easy.
Open up your keyboard settings and pick “Layout Settings”:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install R on OSX</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/02/18/how-to-install-r-on-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 12:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2014/02/18/how-to-install-r-on-osx/</guid>
      <description>Install Homebrew (if needed) ruby -e &amp;quot;$(curl -fsSL \ https://raw.github.com/Homebrew/homebrew/go/install)&amp;quot; Install R brew tap homebrew/science brew install r </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will you be our 1000th customer?</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/10/03/customer1000/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 09:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/10/03/customer1000/</guid>
      <description>Before OddPrints… A short while ago I wanted to print some photos for a little frame (4x4cm). I don’t own a printer and so I wanted to get it printed online. However, the smallest size offered by most online labs is 4×6&amp;quot;. I’m a programmer and amateur photographer, if anyone should find this easy it should be me. How hard can it be?Somehow, I needed to resize and re-save my photo so that it had just the right border around the edge so that when the new image was printed at 4×6&amp;quot; my picture would be in the middle at exactly 4x4cm ready for me to cut out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a smooth loading spinner using only CSS</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/09/04/create-a-smooth-loading-spinner-using-only-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 17:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/09/04/create-a-smooth-loading-spinner-using-only-css/</guid>
      <description>We’ve all seen loading spinners and they generally look like this:
Urgh.
This is just an animated gif and has the following drawbacks:
 Limited to 256 colours Need to regenerate the image if you want a different colour. Framerate and resolution set when you create the image. (and increasing either will hurt load times). Playback is jerky until all frames are downloaded  Wouldn’t it be better to use some vector magic and hardware-accelerated loveliness to get a spinner like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a giant map of everywhere you’ve been</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/07/11/create-a-giant-map-of-everywhere-youve-been/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 16:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/07/11/create-a-giant-map-of-everywhere-youve-been/</guid>
      <description>Google have just announced that they’re giving Latitude the boot. Not in the distant future but next month (August 9th). I’m gutted as I was just getting used to relying on its awesomeness. At first I panicked because I’ve been using the Location History feature to log my location for the past 3 years. Thankfully, that feature is spared the chop (well, for now at least).
If you have also been using it to log your location then you’ll be glad to hear you can download your location history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 reasons to design your logo in CSS (and a few why you shouldn’t)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/02/24/4-reasons-to-design-your-logo-in-css-and-a-few-why-you-shouldnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 19:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/02/24/4-reasons-to-design-your-logo-in-css-and-a-few-why-you-shouldnt/</guid>
      <description>Intro I recently changed the OddPrints logo on the website from an image to simple text styled with CSS and @font-face. To me it seems like the obvious thing to do but very few websites seem to employ the technique. I thought I’d explain my thoughts and I’d love to hear what you think…
1 – Sharper This is the main reason. I recently bought a Retina MacBook Pro and the screen quality is amazing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to track e-commerce sales in Google Analytics with the Google Wallet Java SDK</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/02/14/how-to-track-e-commerce-sales-in-google-analytics-with-the-google-wallet-java-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 14:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2013/02/14/how-to-track-e-commerce-sales-in-google-analytics-with-the-google-wallet-java-sdk/</guid>
      <description>If you have your cart built up in javascript then just follow Google’s documentation. If you submit your Google Wallet cart server-side using the java SDK and want to track the sale using Google Analytics’ ecommerce feature, then this blog is for you…
Before you start, make sure you have enabled the ecommerce feature in Google Analytics.
In your Java code, you need to set the analyticsData (String) in the cart:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a super fast PC in 2013 for just £566</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/12/07/build-a-super-fast-pc-in-2013-for-just-566/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 09:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/12/07/build-a-super-fast-pc-in-2013-for-just-566/</guid>
      <description>Looking to build a new PC? Want to build one that will play nicely with Windows or Linux or could even be a Hackintosh? Making sure you choose the right combination of components is important and a pain to research. If you’re feeling lazy, here’s my shopping list for the machine I built that I’m using right now.
By the way, it’s faaaaaast 😉
CPU – Intel Ivy Bridge (i5-3570K) – £169</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to EC2 from Chrome’s Secure Shell using only a PEM file</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/11/15/connecting-to-ec2-from-chromes-secure-shell-using-only-a-pem-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 10:35:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/11/15/connecting-to-ec2-from-chromes-secure-shell-using-only-a-pem-file/</guid>
      <description>Gee, what a title. I know this post is going to be popular.
First, you need to generate your public key from your private key like this:
ssh-keygen -y -f yourkey.pem &amp;gt; yourkey.pub Then, in Secure Shell, select the “Import…” link to bring up a file picker. You must import two files for each identity. A private key and a public key. For example, you would select both “yourkey.pem” and “yourkey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing photos from a Canon EOS camera with Ubuntu 12.10</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/11/10/importing-photos-from-a-canon-eos-camera-with-ubuntu-12-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 12:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/11/10/importing-photos-from-a-canon-eos-camera-with-ubuntu-12-10/</guid>
      <description>For some reason, when I try to connect my Canon EOS 7D in Linux I get this error:Unable to mount Canon Digital Camera Error initialising camera: -1: Unspecified error  I get no love from lsusb:
matt@beast:~$ lsusb Bus 001 Device 002: ID 8087:0024 Intel Corp. Integrated Rate Matching Hub Bus 002 Device 002: ID 8087:0024 Intel Corp. Integrated Rate Matching Hub Bus 001 Device 001: ID 1d6b:0002 Linux Foundation 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Autumnal Saturday In Bristol</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2012/10/28/an-autumnal-saturday-in-bristol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 18:12:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2012/10/28/an-autumnal-saturday-in-bristol/</guid>
      <description>Blue skies &amp;amp; sunshine with a slight breeze welcomed us as we stepped out of the front door.
Ashton Court 10k. Not me of course. Just Matt. A low key event with the Heart FM guys trying their best to get the “crowds” geared up for cheering the home-coming runners. Especially as the Heart FM Angels were nowhere to be seen. The last time I’d seen them was at the 5k marker halfway up the hill bouncing around with their sparkly pom poms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allow worldwide shipping with Google Checkout/Wallet java SDK</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/10/06/allow-worldwide-shipping-with-google-checkoutwallet-java-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 14:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/10/06/allow-worldwide-shipping-with-google-checkoutwallet-java-sdk/</guid>
      <description>Google’s java SDK for interacting with the checkout API is not a fun experience. It’s generated from the WSDL using JAXB which has a unique ability to generate client interfaces that no human could ever “design”.
It’s not actually that hard to write code with, you just have to think like a deranged machine.
By default, the only allowed shipping destination will be your country. If you wish to allow worldwide shipping, you have to do something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add zero-padding to a folder full of numbered files</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/09/27/how-to-add-zero-padding-to-a-folder-full-of-numbered-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 11:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/09/27/how-to-add-zero-padding-to-a-folder-full-of-numbered-files/</guid>
      <description>Have you got a folder of files that look like this?
file_1.png file_2.png file_3.png file_10.png file_11.png file_12.png file_100.png  But what you really want this:
file_001.png file_002.png file_003.png file_010.png file_011.png file_012.png file_100.png  Then, my linux-loving friend, run this:
rename &#39;s/\d+/sprintf(&amp;quot;%03d&amp;quot;,$&amp;amp;)/e&#39; *.png </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun and games with the new PayPal java SDK</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/08/17/fun-and-games-with-the-new-paypal-java-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 12:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/08/17/fun-and-games-with-the-new-paypal-java-sdk/</guid>
      <description>Up until now I’ve handled my payments for stolencamerafinder and OddPrints with Google Wallet. It’s not fantastic api (I’ve even had to fix it) but it’s pretty straight forward. There’s good documentation and the SDK saves you from writing all that boilerplate for talking to a web service.
I’ve had quite a few requests for allowing PayPal so I’ve spent the last couple of days flicking through their documentation and was quickly shown that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bristol Two Towers Running Challenge</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/07/30/the-bristol-two-towers-running-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 16:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/07/30/the-bristol-two-towers-running-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Fancy a running challenge around Bristol that’ll test your legs and your navigation? All you have to do is touch both Cabot Tower and Troopers Hill Tower (er, chimney) and finish where you started.
 Troopers Hill Tower
 Cabot Tower
The rules are pretty simple:  You have to touch both Cabot Tower and Troopers Hill Tower. Any order. You must start and finish at the same place (of your choice).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install Google Voice</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/07/12/how-to-install-google-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 09:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/07/12/how-to-install-google-voice/</guid>
      <description>Oh jeez, really? A blog post about doing something so easy? Well, yes because it took me about an hour of messing around and so if this helps save one person from the pain, then it’s worth writing. If you’re in a rush or already bored, jump to the short answer.
If you use gmail, you may see the option in the Chat widget to “Call phone”:

Great. Sounds fun, let’s try it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing your credentials in order to deploy to Google App Engine with Ant</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/07/11/passing-your-credentials-in-order-to-deploy-to-google-app-engine-with-ant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 12:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/07/11/passing-your-credentials-in-order-to-deploy-to-google-app-engine-with-ant/</guid>
      <description>If you use the example ant script provided by Google you’ll face the following error:
Your authentication credentials can&#39;t be found and may have expired. Please run appcfg directly from the command line to re-establish your credentials. Sure, you can run appcfg.sh from the console, and login and all will be fine next time. Well, for 24 hours before your credentials are booted from the cache.
Here’s my ant target that does the same thing but takes the credentials interactively using the input task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 319 – Friday 29th July – Tokyo to London – homeward bound</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2012/06/11/day-319-friday-29th-july-tokyo-to-london-homeward-bound/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 18:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2012/06/11/day-319-friday-29th-july-tokyo-to-london-homeward-bound/</guid>
      <description>The final day of an amazing journey. Hop skipping and jumping back from the dream to reality.
I’ll keep it short &amp;amp; sweet as I am writing in retrospect. Part of me doesn’t want to finish this because it’s acceptance that it’s over. But it has to be. And we have moved on and are back doing normal everyday things. And this will surely irritate anyone who reads this now because it is such a cliché but it is true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 318 Thursday 28th July – Tokyo*</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2012/06/11/day-318-thursday-28th-july-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 18:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2012/06/11/day-318-thursday-28th-july-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>Today is a sad day. It’s the penultimate day of our travels. Where has the time gone?
Luckily we’re too exhausted to be that sad. Not that exhausted, however, to look around the huge camera store just across from Tokyo Bus Station. Matt had gone from one dream to another.
We knew if we headed back to K’s House it would be too early to check in so decided to do some last minute sightseeing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you know Sarah who just turned 21? (Windsor, UK)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/04/11/found-21-year-old-sarahs-camera-with-birthday-presents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 20:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/04/11/found-21-year-old-sarahs-camera-with-birthday-presents/</guid>
      <description>This is an appeal to anyone who may know a 21 year old Sarah (born April 6th, 1991) in Windsor, UK. Her camera and other precious items have been found and we want to get them back to her.
 Sarah a celebrated her 21st birthday on friday 6th april. she got picked up by a taxi in windsor on sat morning. a bag containing a pink floral photo album celebrating her life upto her 21st birthday, camera, scarf and other things were left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“F” (The Movie) – Is everyone stupid or is it just me?</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/03/04/f-the-movie-is-everyone-stupid-or-is-it-just-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 11:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/03/04/f-the-movie-is-everyone-stupid-or-is-it-just-me/</guid>
      <description>Spoiler Alert – This will ruin the film if you haven’t seen it.
F
This film started great, a teacher tangled in red tape, falls into depression and alcohol etc etc. But then these supernatural hooded psychos spring into the film and start killing everyone. If that is all the film is then, well, let’s just say it’s not my kind of film.
However, I didn’t think that was what the story was about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first “parkrun”</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/03/03/my-first-parkrun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 10:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/03/03/my-first-parkrun/</guid>
      <description>Today I ran my first parkrun. If like me you’ve never heard of them:
 parkrun organise free, weekly, 5km timed runs around the world. They are open to everyone, free, and are safe and easy to take part in.
 Pretty simple really. You just register for free on the website for a personal barcode, print it out then turn up and race. You just register as a runner, not for individual races, it’s up to you which races you attend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My recommendation for your first SLR in 2012</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/02/27/my-recommendation-for-your-first-slr-in-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 11:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/02/27/my-recommendation-for-your-first-slr-in-2012/</guid>
      <description>Want better photos? As I’ve mentioned before, I get asked what camera to buy a lot. I mean loads, it’s silly. Generally, I get asked by people who are fed up with the blurry, grainy photos they are currently taking and think a new camera will solve everything. If this sounds like you, then go read my previous post about whether or not an SLR is for you.
Done? Still interested?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing JavaScript with QUnit for for Dummies, sorry, Java developers</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/01/11/testing-javascript-with-quni/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 13:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2012/01/11/testing-javascript-with-quni/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I’m no javascript expert so I may be am almost certainly talking a load of rubbish here.
I was just looking for a unit testing framework for some javascript I’m writing (rather the the home-rolled framework I’ve out-grown) and came across QUnit. I’ve not tried any others so feel free to suggest alternatives. So far, it’s great and does everything I want and took me almost no time to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cheapest way to get a Samsung Galaxy S2 in the UK</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/12/07/the-cheapest-way-to-get-a-samsung-galaxy-s2-in-the-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 12:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/12/07/the-cheapest-way-to-get-a-samsung-galaxy-s2-in-the-uk/</guid>
      <description>If you’re a materialistic idiot like me, you’ll be interested in how you can get your hands on a disgustingly extravagant smartphone while parting with the least amount of cash possible.
The best deal I found for the Galaxy S2 (by far) has been through Tesco:
 Free handset T-Mobile network 300 mins/300 texts 24 month contract Free delivery 500MB Data Booster + Unlimited Internet £20 of free apps available (through some T&amp;amp;Cs) £20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night 317 Wednesday 27th July – Climbing Fuji-san</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/11/16/night-317-wednesday-27th-july-climbing-fuji-san/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 19:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/11/16/night-317-wednesday-27th-july-climbing-fuji-san/</guid>
      <description>This is it, our final adventure of the trip. We’ve ridden camels across the desert, boated up the Ganges, hiked along the Nepalese border, zip-lined across waterfalls, trodden through jungle with elephants, tandem-navigated vineyards, thrown ourselves out of a plane and off a cable-car, crashed a campervan, scuba-dived in the Great Barrier Reef, seen the Taj Mahal, the Petronas Towers, Angkor Wat &amp;amp; the Sydney Opera House. Now we’re off to climb 6km through the night to reach the summit of Mt Fuji, the highest mountain in Japan, in time for sunrise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 317 Wednesday 27th July – Tokyo</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/11/16/day-317-wednesday-27th-july-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/11/16/day-317-wednesday-27th-july-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>This may say this blog post is for 27th July but I am trying to write it up on 7th November, 103 days after the occasion so please accept my apologies for the tediousness.
I have no idea why Japan has taken me so long to write about and how I made time whilst travelling to write up the rest of the travels is a weird one. Anyone who reads this may think why the hell am I bothering when it was so long ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 316 Tuesday 26th July – Kyoto &amp; Tokyo – Tokyo Dome baseball</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/11/16/day-316-tuesday-26th-july-kyoto-tokyo-tokyo-dome-baseball/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/11/16/day-316-tuesday-26th-july-kyoto-tokyo-tokyo-dome-baseball/</guid>
      <description>Back to Tokyo again today. Our final trip on the Shinkansen and I think we have got our money’s worth.
Based on Google maps we did a total of 1104 miles which is about ¥25 per mile (approx 20p). That’s cheaper than our old RX-8 (when we were materialistic and had money to spend on silly cars).
In detail for anyone who likes this kind of stuff, like me, the distances were Tokyo –&amp;gt; Hiroshima (507 miles), Hiroshima –&amp;gt; Miyajima (16 miles), Miyajima –&amp;gt; Hiroshima (16 miles), Hiroshima –&amp;gt; Kyoto (224 miles), Kyoto –&amp;gt; Nara (26 miles), Nara –&amp;gt; Kyoto (26 miles), Kyoto –&amp;gt; Tokyo (289 miles).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify your API – Can Singletons be used for Good, not Evil?</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/11/14/simplify-your-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 15:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/11/14/simplify-your-api/</guid>
      <description>I recently wrote an article about singletons in java. The only thing I wanted to cover was that if you really want a singleton, I recommend you use the enum pattern. This post was motivated after more interesting comments were raised about testability when you see the “static” keyword.
When you type “static” a little alarm bell should ring in your head to warn you that there could be trouble ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 315 Monday 25th July – Kyoto &amp; Osaka – Ryoan-ji &amp; Kinkaku-ji temples &#43; Tenjin Matsuri festival</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/28/day-315-monday-25th-july-kyoto-osaka-ryoan-ji-kinkaku-ji-temples-tenjin-matsuri-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/28/day-315-monday-25th-july-kyoto-osaka-ryoan-ji-kinkaku-ji-temples-tenjin-matsuri-festival/</guid>
      <description>We hadn’t planned on going to Osaka as we didn’t think we would have enough time but the guy at the hostel mentioned there would be a big festival there today starting at 3pm so we felt we should go and have a look.
The thing is we had also been recommended some other temples in Kyoto and tomorrow we’re off back to Tokyo so we had to get up early to get it all in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bug with JQuery validation error messages showing tooltip text</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/28/bug-with-jquery-validation-error-messages-showing-tooltip-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 13:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/28/bug-with-jquery-validation-error-messages-showing-tooltip-text/</guid>
      <description>I had the following html in my form:
&amp;lt;label for=&amp;quot;email-input&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Email&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt; &amp;amp;lt;input id=&amp;quot;email-input&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text&amp;quot; title=&amp;quot;Don&#39;t worry, your email will not be displayed on the website or given to anyone else. We hate spam too.&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; Nothing complicated there I hope.
I had the help text set in the title attribute of the input which I styled with the lovely qTip to make it look nice. I validated my entry using the jQuery validation plugin which also works well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to enable Offline Google Docs for Google Apps users</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/26/how-to-enable-offline-google-docs-for-google-apps-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 14:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/26/how-to-enable-offline-google-docs-for-google-apps-users/</guid>
      <description>Do you still not have the offline option for Google Docs?
If you’re a Google Apps user, then your apps administrator has to enable it first:
 Log in to the Google Apps control panel at https://www.google.com/a/your_domain.com (replace _your_domain.com_with your actual domain name). From the menu bar at the top of the page, click Settings. In the left menu, click Docs. Select the Allow users to enable offline docs check box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write Singletons in java</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/26/how-to-write-singletons-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 11:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/26/how-to-write-singletons-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Singletons get a pretty bad press. Often described as an “anti-pattern”. I think it’s a little unfair since I find them pretty useful in several situations. However, the reason they can be bad is important to understand:
 Making a class a singleton can make it difficult to test its clients, as it’s impossible to substitute a mock implementation for a singleton unless it implements an interface that serves as its type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 314 Sunday 24th July – Kyoto &amp; Nara</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/14/day-314-sunday-24th-july-kyoto-nara/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/14/day-314-sunday-24th-july-kyoto-nara/</guid>
      <description>Not content with staying in one place for very long off we popped to Nara, the old capital of Japan from 710 to 784AD, 45 mins on the train from Kyoto.
They are revamping the train station so it took us 30 mins to find the bicycle hire place which turned out to be right out of the station instead of left.
We intended to hire normal bikes but of course they had electric ones so who could resist?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 313 Saturday 23rd July – Kyoto – Gion temples, lanterns, tea &amp; sushi</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/14/day-313-saturday-23rd-july-kyoto-gion-temples-lanterns-tea-sushi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 19:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/14/day-313-saturday-23rd-july-kyoto-gion-temples-lanterns-tea-sushi/</guid>
      <description>It is very very hot today. brought back memories of India &amp;amp; SE Asia, carrying our backpacks through searing sunshine.
After our 3rd visit in as many days to Bakery Roti around the corner from J Hoppers, our favourite supplier of random bakery items, we struggled onto a packed tram with all the shoppers. Stares were a plenty as we blocked the narrow alleyways with our ugly luggage. It was a relief to get onto the cool air-conditioned Shinkansen to Kyoto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 312 cont… Friday 22nd July – Miyajima – Itsukushima Shrine &amp; Torii gate</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/14/rm-day-312-cont-friday-22nd-july-miyajima-itsukushima-shrine-torii-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 19:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/14/rm-day-312-cont-friday-22nd-july-miyajima-itsukushima-shrine-torii-gate/</guid>
      <description>After such a sobering morning we needed a lighter afternoon.
A tram, train &amp;amp; ferry trip later and we were on Miyajima island, home of the Itsukushima Shrine, its famous floating torii gate and countless tame wild deer always looking for food.
It’s a pretty little place with a coastal promenade and one street of cute little shops that even the deer fancied popping into for some retail therapy.
At the end of the promenade you get a full view of the torii gate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 312 Friday 22nd July – Hiroshima – Peace Memorial Museum</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-312-friday-22nd-july-hiroshima-peace-memorial-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-312-friday-22nd-july-hiroshima-peace-memorial-museum/</guid>
      <description>Spent the morning at the Peace Memorial Museum, a very modern building containing some of the most horrific sights I have ever seen.You are shown information about the lead-up to the day the A-bomb was dropped. Who made the bomb, who made the decisions on where and when to drop it and why. I am still shocked at how that was decision was made. It was an experiment. An unknown. How would it affect human life?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 311 Thursday 21st July – Hiroshima</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-311-thursday-21st-july-hiroshima/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 20:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-311-thursday-21st-july-hiroshima/</guid>
      <description>Guess what? It’s our penultimate Thursday.
We took the Shinkansen to Hiroshima. Otherwise known as the bullet train, it lives up to its reputation. It was on time and it was zippy. If you try to walk whilst it’s moving you feel like you’re floating and have no control over your core balance. It has a similar feel to a plane. Except with miles more legroom and much better food. We happened to miss the snack lady as she passed so I went up to purchase something from her and she waved me back to my seat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 310 Wednesday 20th July – Tokyo</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-310-wednesday-20th-july-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 19:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-310-wednesday-20th-july-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>It’s our penultimate Wednesday of the trip and we’re in Japan.
We thought it would be difficult to work out anything as Matt knows zero Japanese and my night class at uni has all but disintegrated from my memory leaving hello, goodbye, my name is Karen and the numbers 1 to 4. We needn’t have worried (when I say we I mean I as Matt never worries about anything). Most things at the airport were in English as well as Japanese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 309 Tuesday 19th July – Sydney &amp; the end of Australia leg</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-309-tuesday-19th-july-sydney-the-end-of-australia-leg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-309-tuesday-19th-july-sydney-the-end-of-australia-leg/</guid>
      <description>Hopped on the 9:20 train back to Sydney and at Central Station were planning on walking to the Harbour Bridge but made a rash decision to get another train leaving in 3 mins to Milson’s Point, the train station the other side of the Harbour bridge, or so we hoped.
The train travelled underground to Town Hall, then to Wyndham and when the voice over the tannoy said “next stop Milson’s Point” and we started slowing down we were still in darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 308 Monday 18th July – Blue Mountains</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-308-monday-18th-july-blue-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 19:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-308-monday-18th-july-blue-mountains/</guid>
      <description>We are on a roll. We caught the rush hour bus to town, managed to get the one that didn’t go near the station which led to us leaping from the bus at Hyde Park at 9am, legging it to Central Station, buying tickets in a flash (there was absolutely zero queue – what is that all about in the main station of a huge city?), skipping through the barriers and onto the top floor of the double-decker parked on platform 6 with 1 min to spare for the 9:09 to Katoomba.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 307 Sunday 17th July – Sydney – opera house, harbour bridge &amp; all that jazz &#43; Manly</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-307-sunday-17th-july-sydney-opera-house-harbour-bridge-all-that-jazz-manly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-307-sunday-17th-july-sydney-opera-house-harbour-bridge-all-that-jazz-manly/</guid>
      <description>We saw the Opera House and the Harbour Bridge today. So excited! It didn’t seem real that we were actually in Sydney until we saw them. And it still doesn’t seem real now.
Stood looking the the Opera House for ages. The base of it is pretty ugly which consists of beige concrete and it is difficult to see the famous iconic shape of it from the bottom. But it doesn’t matter as you can get up close to the Swedish (?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 306 Saturday 16th July – Sydney – Coogee Beach to Bondi Beach</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-306-saturday-16th-july-sydney-coogee-beach-to-bondi-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 17:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/day-306-saturday-16th-july-sydney-coogee-beach-to-bondi-beach/</guid>
      <description>Another nice early start and we were at Cairns domestic airport at 5:30 queuing Easyjet-stylie at the Virgin Blue check-in desks. We had checked in online to “save time”. We stood in the “Bag Drop Off” line for 25mins whilst people arriving late for the Brisbane flight were called forward followed by whoever felt like it from any of the lines. I wasn’t the only one mumbling under my breath I can tell you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s only taken me 74 days but...</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/its-only-taken-me-74-days-but/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 17:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/10/12/its-only-taken-me-74-days-but/</guid>
      <description>… here come the rest of the travel blogs (well days 306 to 314 for starters).
Better late than never…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to dynamically choose the color of your Google maps marker pin using javascript</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/07/how-to-dynamically-choose-the-color-of-you-google-maps-marker-pin-using-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 12:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/07/how-to-dynamically-choose-the-color-of-you-google-maps-marker-pin-using-javascript/</guid>
      <description>You can dynamically request icon images from the Google charts api with the urls:
 http://chart.apis.google.com/chart?chst=d_map_pin_letter&amp;amp;chld=%E2%80%A2|FE7569
 Which looks like this:the image is 21×43 pixels and the pin tip is at position (10, 34)
And you’ll also want a separate shadow image (so that it doesn’t overlap nearby icons):
 http://chart.apis.google.com/chart?chst=d_map_pin_shadow
 Which looks like this:the image is 40×37 pixels and the pin tip is at position (12, 35)
When you construct your MarkerImages you need to set the size and achor points accordingly:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get the “WINDOWS USB Driver” for your LG mobile</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/03/how-to-get-the-windows-usb-driver-for-your-lg-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 09:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/10/03/how-to-get-the-windows-usb-driver-for-your-lg-mobile/</guid>
      <description>If you’re trying to update your LG mobile (I’m doing my LG Arena KM900) you will be taken to a page that tells you to install the WINDOWS USB Driver, whatever that is.
At time of writing, that link doesn’t work.
Don’t worry, just go ahead and click “Software Update” as there is the option to install the usb driver there. If you also need the PC Suite, I found a copy here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My next e-book</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/09/16/my-next-e-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 18:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/09/16/my-next-e-book/</guid>
      <description>If you know me, you’ll know I just got back from a year galavanting around the world. I was given a Sony e-book as a present which I took with me, and soon became an essential item.
It’s already showing its age compared to newer models but I’m not buying a new one until e-book manufacturers start adding features I actually want.
I don’t want:
 A colour screen. Why would I?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 year ago today…</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/09/14/1-year-ago-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 09:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/09/14/1-year-ago-today/</guid>
      <description>…we were at Heathrow Terminal 5 sitting down and fastening our seatbelts on our flight to Delhi off on a round half the world adventure (which we almost missed because someone had been distracted by the shiny things on display in the Sony shop).
We’ve had the most amazing year. Although we got back to the UK over 6 weeks ago, we are still travelling. Catching up with friends and family all over and seeing the UK from a different point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to print small photos (say, 4cm x 4cm)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/09/10/how-to-print-small-photos-say-4cm-x-4cm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2011 12:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/09/10/how-to-print-small-photos-say-4cm-x-4cm/</guid>
      <description>If you have a photo you want to put into a small frame, you may struggle finding a print company that print photos smaller than 15cm x 10cm (6&amp;quot;x4&amp;quot;).
The simple answer is to create add a white border to your jpeg and print that. Then you can just trim the edges off the print. I just tried this and it was harder than I would have liked. If you open your photo in some software and expand the canvas, you’ll find it will start eating lots of memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting Child Entities with GQL Queries</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/08/23/selecting-child-entities-with-gql-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 17:14:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/08/23/selecting-child-entities-with-gql-queries/</guid>
      <description>In Google App Engine, you can create owned one-to-many relationships between entities. The classic example you were taught at uni is that a Book owns a Chapter, which in turn, owns a Paragraph. For my site, stolencamerafinder, the example is that a camera Make owns a set of Models.
If you want to query for the model directly in GQL (from the app engine dashboard for example) you can create the key by specifying the full parent chain:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye bye rest of world, hello UK</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/29/bye-bye-rest-of-world-hello-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2011 01:57:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/29/bye-bye-rest-of-world-hello-uk/</guid>
      <description>OK so I haven’t updated the blog yet for the rest of Australia &amp;amp; Japan but it’s our last few minutes before getting on our final flight of the trip back to sunny England. We can’t quite believe it. 10 months and 15 days. It’s really over. Can’t quite believe it. Looking forward to seeing family &amp;amp; friends but not being back to reality. Have no idea what that is like now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 303 to 305 Wednesday 13th to Friday 15th July – Cairns</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/26/day-303-to-305-wednesday-13th-to-friday-15th-july-cairns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 06:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/26/day-303-to-305-wednesday-13th-to-friday-15th-july-cairns/</guid>
      <description>We decided to stay in Cairns for the rest of the week. As much as we want to see Port Douglas and Cape Tribulation we are running short on funds and want to make the most of Sydney &amp;amp; Japan so we have to compromise.
I won’t bore you with the details (as I have in the 302 days previously) so here’s the overview of Cairns post-diving.
Interesting graffiti &amp;amp; sculpture just off Grafton Street near a kooky little cafe called Caffiend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 302 Tuesday 12th July – diving in Great Barrier Reef</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/26/day-302-tuesday-12th-july-diving-in-great-barrier-reef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 05:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/26/day-302-tuesday-12th-july-diving-in-great-barrier-reef/</guid>
      <description>It was still dark when the alarm sounded at 5:45. It’s becoming a common occurrence with us, early mornings. Are we old? (We definitely have the crows feet &amp;amp; grey hair these days. It’s hard work all this travelling malarkey.)
But this was for a much better reason than some bus driver waking us up to get a move on. We were off diving!
We had to be at the marina by 7 and by some miracle were up and dressed with cheesy vegemite coated toast in hand we were out the side gate, a swift gallivant through town and down to the boat RedKist on pier E (or finger as they call it here?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 301 Monday 11th July – Cairns</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/23/day-301-monday-11th-july-cairns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 16:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/23/day-301-monday-11th-july-cairns/</guid>
      <description>…I was wrong. In Thailand you expect to veer off the road into a tree at any time but at least the seats are suited to overnight travel. The Greyhound buses in Oz are the worst for sleeping on. Their seats are just a little too small to curl up on so you can never get comfy. The aircon was on so it was cold too. And to top it off the onboard loo wasn’t functioning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 300 Sunday 10th July – Magnetic Island &amp; onto Cairns</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/23/day-300-sunday-10th-july-magnetic-island-onto-cairns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 16:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/23/day-300-sunday-10th-july-magnetic-island-onto-cairns/</guid>
      <description>Pretty much all of our 300th day was on Magnetic Island. Actually right up til the 21:30 ferry.
Another fabulous sunshiny day, waking up to the sounds of birds and wildlife squawking and ferreting around outside the bungalow. Brekkie in amongst the rainforest (kind of), a couple hours of wifi to finally book our flights from Cairns – we’re skipping Melbourne and off to Sydney as want to spend more time in the sun whilst we can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 299 Saturday 9th July – Magnetic Island &amp; more Aussie wildlife</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/23/day-299-saturday-9th-july-magnetic-island-more-aussie-wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 15:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/23/day-299-saturday-9th-july-magnetic-island-more-aussie-wildlife/</guid>
      <description>Woke early to the sun shining through the perspex windows and birds chirping &amp;amp; chuckling. There is a wildlife sanctuary in the grounds of our accommodation which offer the opportunity to cuddle a koala. Matt wanted to get a photo of me doing this (and I wasn’t adverse to holding a koala either) so we joined in the tour. We both expected it to be cheesy and for kids. It was both but also now another favourite thing we’ve done on our trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 298 Friday 8th July – Magnetic Island</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/23/day-298-friday-8th-july-magnetic-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 15:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/23/day-298-friday-8th-july-magnetic-island/</guid>
      <description>Greyhound were in our bad books. We dragged ourselves out of bed whilst it was still dark to get the 7am bus so that we could get out of Airlie Beach and to Magnetic Island as soon as possible.
Instead we had to wait in a carpark, watching the sun rise, which admittedly was pretty, for an extra hour and ten minutes.
There was no apology or explanation when it finally arrived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 297 Thursday 7th July – Airlie Beach</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/22/day-297-thursday-7th-july-airlie-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 15:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/22/day-297-thursday-7th-july-airlie-beach/</guid>
      <description>Airlie Beach is the “jumping off point” (LP says this all the time and I hate it with a passion!) for Whitsunday sailings.
We decided not to bother. They were really expensive and we want to go diving in the Great Barrier Reef from Cairns so we’ll only be staying here a day.
The thing is there isn’t much else here. Well there is. It has a street of restaurants and bars and backpackers and travel agents selling sailing trips and a man-made lagoon because you can’t go in the water because of the crocodiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 295 &amp; 296 Tuesday 5th &amp; Wednesday 6th July – Agnes Water/1770</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/22/day-295-296-tuesday-5th-wednesday-6th-july-agnes-water1770/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2011 15:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/22/day-295-296-tuesday-5th-wednesday-6th-july-agnes-water1770/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday we had our second surf lesson. The water was calmer and the boards were slipperier and we just couldn’t stand up. We are obviously much better in rougher waves. We blame the boards. Still it was fun stuff and we went back on Wednesday for another lesson. This time there were too many people so we just hired our own boards and wetsuits and headed to the beach. We were still pretty terrible but we won’t give up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 294 Monday 4th July – Hervey Bay &amp; Agnes Water / Town of 1770</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-294-monday-4th-july-hervey-bay-agnes-water-town-of-1770/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 07:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-294-monday-4th-july-hervey-bay-agnes-water-town-of-1770/</guid>
      <description>Our bus wasn’t until 14:25 and the guy at the hostel couldn’t have been nicer. Maybe because we hadn’t been so impressed with his recommendation. We could use all the facilities until we left and he’d give us a lift to the bus station.
So we borrowed the bikes again and yes today is another scorcher. It’s the hottest we’ve felt it in Oz.
And off we cycled in the heat to the 826metre pier and walked to the end passing countless fisherpeople.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 293 Sunday 3rd July – Fraser Island</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-293-sunday-3rd-july-fraser-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 07:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-293-sunday-3rd-july-fraser-island/</guid>
      <description>Unsure what to make of today.
We were off the magical place of Fraser Island. A top destination for anyone visiting the East Coast of Australia, apparently.
We’d been “sold” the bus trip by the guy at our hostel. We were going to do the 2-day 1-night camping but that was sold out so we were going to do the 1-day jeep but somehow he managed to persuade us the bus would be better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 292 Saturday 2nd July – Hervey Bay</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-292-saturday-2nd-july-hervey-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-292-saturday-2nd-july-hervey-bay/</guid>
      <description>THE SUN IS SHINING!
We have found the sun at last. Proper hot sun. The real skin-crisping kind. MIA since Sihanoukville. Although I guess you could say Siem Reap was hot &amp;amp; sunny but there could be no sunbathing there unless you wanted to look like a KFC family bucket.
Hearing rumours of kangaroos grazing at the north tip of Hervey Bay we borrowed bikes and followed the bike track along the esplanade for 6 or 7km until we reached a sandy bay we couldn’t resist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 291 Friday 1st July – Noosa National Park, Hervey Bay &amp; Australian wildlife</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-291-friday-1st-july-noosa-national-park-hervey-bay-australian-wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 06:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-291-friday-1st-july-noosa-national-park-hervey-bay-australian-wildlife/</guid>
      <description>Noooo it can’t be 1st July already? That means only 4 weeks left. Better make the most of it then.
Up nice &amp;amp; early with the idea of going for a 3 hour walk through Noosa National Park to spot wild koalas and kookaburras before catching the lunchtime bus to Hervey Bay.
On checking out the girl says “have you seen the koala at the end of the driveway”? And there he was sat calm as anything back to the world clinging onto the high branches on a eucalyptus tree next to the busy roundabout by our hostel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 290 Thursday 30th June – Noosa – surf lessons</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-290-thursday-30th-june-noosa-surf-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 06:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-290-thursday-30th-june-noosa-surf-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Learned to surf today! You’d think by now we’d know how to use the internet (dad joke).
Anyhoo the sea was really rough with huge waves and we were both battered and bruised to within an inch of our lives but thoroughly enjoyed it. We even managed to stand on the board a few times. Credit to the surf teacher dude.
We enjoyed it so much we’re going to make sure we can surf again before we leave Oz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 289 Wednesday 29th June – Noosa</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-289-wednesday-29th-june-noosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 06:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-289-wednesday-29th-june-noosa/</guid>
      <description>Arrived in Noosa after a pleasant Greyhound trip to find the sun ablazing. Yahoo!
As everyone else moved off into their designated pickup mini-buses, we being the usual turn up and see, decided on the YHA for its closest proximity to the bus stop (we now seem to be carting around a total of 6 bags – 2 backpacks, 2 rucksacks, 1 bag of souvenirs and a coolbag) and turns out the lovely Noosa Heads beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 288 Tuesday 28th June – Brisbane</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-288-tuesday-28th-june-brisbane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 06:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-288-tuesday-28th-june-brisbane/</guid>
      <description>Last night we got back to Acacia to find a breakfast basket on our bed. I forgot to mention we do actually have a fridge, kettle (an actual electric jug*!) &amp;amp; toaster in the room – bonus. Anyway the brekkie basket consisted of 2 bowls, 2 plates, a mini-pack of weet-bix for moi, a mini-pack of cornflakes for matt, 2 half pint cartons of milk (like what you get in playschool milk), two tetrapaks of OJ and portions of butter, jam &amp;amp; vegemite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 287 Monday 27th June – AUSTRALIA – Brisbane</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-287-monday-27th-june-australia-brisbane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 06:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/19/day-287-monday-27th-june-australia-brisbane/</guid>
      <description>We made it.
2:30 alarm.
3:15 left apartment.
3:35 on bus to airport.
4:10 check in.
4:40 security check – Matt gets searched twice – he’s got the hoody and the beanie but of course it is random.
6:00 (NZ time) on the easyjet style plane for an uneasy flight. You would have thought by now with a helicopter ride up glaciers, bungy jumping over a canyon and a light aircraft flight 15000m up to fall out into the sky, a 4 hour flight would be a doddle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 286 Sunday 26th June – Auckland</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/17/day-286-sunday-26th-june-auckland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 12:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/17/day-286-sunday-26th-june-auckland/</guid>
      <description>We moved to Waldorf Tetra apartments. It was sad to leave Hotel deBrett. And having 4 hours to kill between check-out and check-in consisted of sitting by the harbour and window-shopping. We’d quite like to get to Australia now please.
Proof we saw a bit of Auckland.The Tetra apartment is in a not so wonderful location but it’s still pretty close to the centre and we have been upgraded to a two-bedroom apartment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 285 – Saturday 25th June – Auckland</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/17/day-285-saturday-25th-june-auckland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 12:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/17/day-285-saturday-25th-june-auckland/</guid>
      <description>We’d quite like to leave tomorrow now. But flights are cancelled again all day. So we’re now on a Monday flight.
This is a slight pain as it means 4 nights in Auckland. Qantas will only pay for 3 so we have to move somewhere cheaper.
We don’t want to leave Hotel deBrett!
Being in limbo waiting to see if our flights are on or off has meant being completely lazy in Auckland and just playing the waiting game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 284 – Friday 24th June – Auckland</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/14/day-284-friday-24th-june-auckland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/14/day-284-friday-24th-june-auckland/</guid>
      <description>Another day in Auckland. Another cancelled flight tomorrow. Booked in for Sunday evening.
Qantas will pay for 3 nights accommodation so Sunday will be good for us 😀
There is nothing to complain about at Hotel deBrett. The breakfast was divine. Fresh fruit, proper coffee and delicious pastries. Pre-dinner drinks in the Drawing Room were proper drinks. I sound so common but most “free” drinks in hotels are usually the cheapest most generic thing they can think of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 283 (6874km to 6903km 50/0) Thursday 23rd June – Auckland</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/14/day-283-6874km-to-6903km-500-thursday-23rd-june-auckland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/14/day-283-6874km-to-6903km-500-thursday-23rd-june-auckland/</guid>
      <description>Bye bye New Zealand in a campervan…
…hello New Zealand in a beautiful hotel.
So we’re meant to be in Sydney now but instead we’re in a gorgeous hotel in the centre of Auckland.
Qantas told us we have a budget of $250 AUD to spend on accommodation per day so we’ve booked ourselves into the best hotel in central Auckland. Well why not?!
After taking a couple of wrong turns and ending up on the motorway and then back where we started we finally made it to Wilderness where they were happy with everything we’d paid for for the van’s bump previously and we had no other costs to pay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 282 (6451km to 6873km 49/1) Wednesday 22nd June – new van, Kauri trees, Auckland &amp; Chilean ash clouds</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/14/day-282-6451km-to-6873km-491-wednesday-22nd-june-new-van-kauri-trees-auckland-chilean-ash-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 00:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/14/day-282-6451km-to-6873km-491-wednesday-22nd-june-new-van-kauri-trees-auckland-chilean-ash-clouds/</guid>
      <description>Steve from Wilderness turned up at 8:30am after driving from Auckland with our new van. It is so clean!
hello new van (parked outside the motel room)The breakdown and motel in its way had been a blessing in disguise. We’d used the vast space in the room to organise ourselves and managed to get most of our gear packed up so we’ll be ready for our flight. I doubt we’d have been this organised if we’d still been travelling around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 281 (6414km to 6450 48/2) Tuesday 21st June – The Breakdown – no Cape Reinga, no 90-mile beach, back to Whangarei</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-281-6414km-to-6450-482-tuesday-21st-june-the-breakdown-no-cape-reinga-no-90-mile-beach-back-to-whangarei/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 09:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-281-6414km-to-6450-482-tuesday-21st-june-the-breakdown-no-cape-reinga-no-90-mile-beach-back-to-whangarei/</guid>
      <description>Not a breakdown of the mental kind (just yet) but the mechanical kind. The clutch to be accurate.
We had been indecisive yesterday about whether to drive the 110k to Cape Reinga and back. Did we have time to fit it in? It would be a 4 hour round trip up and back down the peninsula and we wanted to get to Auckland on Wednesday with time to spare to see the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 280 (6109km to 6413km 47/3) Monday 20th June – Tukatata, Hundertwasser toilets, ferry to Russell &amp; Karikari peninsula campsite</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-280-6109km-to-6413km-473-monday-20th-june-tukatata-hundertwasser-toilets-ferry-to-russell-karikari-peninsula-campsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 09:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-280-6109km-to-6413km-473-monday-20th-june-tukatata-hundertwasser-toilets-ferry-to-russell-karikari-peninsula-campsite/</guid>
      <description>Today was a different story. It was action-packed to the gills.
Awoke to a very cool view out the back of the van. Not a bad little campsite location-wise. Shame about the cold showers.
First stop was Whangarei. We weren’t going to bother as we’d heard it wasn’t a very interesting town. But we thought as we’re passing through and this would be the only time we’d ever have the chance to see the largest falls in NZ, we’d stop for 5 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 279 (5944km to 6108km 46/4) Sunday 19th June – Ruakaka</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-279-5944km-to-6108km-464-sunday-19th-june-ruakaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 08:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-279-5944km-to-6108km-464-sunday-19th-june-ruakaka/</guid>
      <description>We left Isla &amp;amp; Neil’s around lunchtime laden down with oranges freshly picked from the garden and headed to Northland.
It was absolutely peeing it down.
I am writing this in retrospect and can’t for once remember what we actually did apart from stop for petrol &amp;amp; supermarket supplies in Warkworth and go to a campsite in Ruakaka. Which sounds like a pretty boring afternoon. But I guess every day can’t be filled with exciting moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 278 (5942km to 5942km 45/5) Saturday 18th June–Auckland</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-278-5942km-to-5942km-455-saturday-18th-juneauckland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 08:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-278-5942km-to-5942km-455-saturday-18th-juneauckland/</guid>
      <description>Feeling pretty hanging today after all that red wine.
Isla &amp;amp; Neil were excellent tour guides despite the headaches. Took us to Muahai to see the gannet colony, unfortunately this was the only time of the year when there were no gannets. Almost got washed away when an surprise wave covered us.
Next stop Auckland Museum where we had to put on our best Kiwi accents to get an Aucklander free entry sticker followed by a stroll along Mission Bay &amp;amp; a drive around Auckland city centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 277 (5755km to 5941km 44/6) Friday 17th June – Auckland</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-277-5755km-to-5941km-446-friday-17th-june-auckland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 08:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-277-5755km-to-5941km-446-friday-17th-june-auckland/</guid>
      <description>Had a nose around Coromandel town and not much was going on. A few little cafes &amp;amp; souvenir shops plus a bakery that served up good seafood pie.
Drove down the west coast of the peninsula with lovely views all the way, then stopped at the most random place for lunch next to a bird reserve with no views of the sea.
Managed to make it to Auckland mid-afternoon and can’t get over the size of the place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 276 (5503km to 5754km 43/7) Thursday 16th June – Hot Water Beach, Cathedral Cave, Coromandel</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-276-5503km-to-5754km-437-thursday-16th-june-hot-water-beach-cathedral-cave-coromandel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 08:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-276-5503km-to-5754km-437-thursday-16th-june-hot-water-beach-cathedral-cave-coromandel/</guid>
      <description>Our morning consisted of digging a hole in the sand and sitting in a shallow pool of water trying to keep it at a pleasant temperature which seemed near impossible as cold water shot out of one area and scolding hot water came out of another.
We were at Hot Water Beach.
Lunch at the beach.The afternoon consisted of a 30min stomp along the coastline to catch the last of the sun on 2 secluded beaches divided by Cathedral Cove.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 275 (5423km to 5502km 42/8) Wednesday 15th June – Tauranga</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-275-5423km-to-5502km-428-wednesday-15th-june-tauranga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 08:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-275-5423km-to-5502km-428-wednesday-15th-june-tauranga/</guid>
      <description>Didn’t get very far today. The plan had been to see Tauranga in the morning and start heading up to Coromandel this afternoon. We’re still in Tauranga.
Started off at the art gallery for a bit of culture. It was very nice.
Stopped for a yummy coffee &amp;amp; delicious home-baked sausage roll at the Dry Dock Cafe where we chatted to the owner who has inspired me even more to run my own business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 274 (5503km to 5422km 41/9) Tuesday 14th June – Rotorua &amp; Maketu</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-274-5503km-to-5422km-419-tuesday-14th-june-rotorua-maketu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 08:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-274-5503km-to-5422km-419-tuesday-14th-june-rotorua-maketu/</guid>
      <description>We have been away for 9 months now.
Awoke to a chillier day and made for another local attraction – the 10am opening of the dam. An amazing piece of engineering, apparently. Pulled up in the car park at 9:40 and made a nice cup of tea before wandering over 10 mins later to wait for the dam to open.
It finally dawned on us 15 mins later that the dam was already open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 273 (5204km to 5260km 40/10) Monday 13th June – Taupō</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-273-5204km-to-5260km-4010-monday-13th-june-taupo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 02:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-273-5204km-to-5260km-4010-monday-13th-june-taupo/</guid>
      <description>Glorious sunshine filled the crystal clear blue skies and what was going to be a quiet day with a quick visit to the thermal spa and then onto Rotorua turned into another adrenaline-filled day in the form of SKYDIVING!
At 10:40 we thought we’d just ring up to enquire about how much it was and if they were flying today.
An hour later we were at the centre getting into our gear and at 12:45 we were climbing into Taupō Tandem Skydive’s banana coloured plane with a large toothy grin on the front (of the plane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 272 (5105km to 5203km 39/11) Sunday 12th June – Taupō</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-272-5105km-to-5203km-3911-sunday-12th-june-taupo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 01:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-272-5105km-to-5203km-3911-sunday-12th-june-taupo/</guid>
      <description>Whilst having our breakfast overlooking the lake we were suddenly surrounded by cars. What is going on? We are in the middle of nowhere again but all these people are turning up and getting out of their cars with their thermos’ to have a natter. It finally dawns on us they are most probably here for some memorial as almost all of them are wearing black. And there we are munching on toast with the radio blaring out Katy Perry &amp;amp; Lady Gaga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 271 (4846km to 5104km 38/12) Saturday 11th June – Hastings, Hawkes bay wine-tasting &amp; Art Deco Napier</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-271-4846km-to-5104km-3812-saturday-11th-june-hastings-hawkes-bay-wine-tasting-art-deco-napier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 01:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-271-4846km-to-5104km-3812-saturday-11th-june-hastings-hawkes-bay-wine-tasting-art-deco-napier/</guid>
      <description>The sun is out again. And it’s actually quite mild.
Didn’t sleep too well as spooked out by being in a campsite in the middle of nowhere surrounded by loud rustling trees and, so it turns out, fields of sheep.
Hawkes Bay is another famous wine region in NZ. Spent an hour in Hastings. It has a train track running through the centre of a fountain.
Wine-tasted at one cellar door called Black Barn near Havelock North.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 270 (4613km to 4845km 37/13) Friday 10th June – Mt Victoria, M1, Palmerston &amp; Kumeti DOC campsite</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-270-4613km-to-4845km-3713-friday-10th-june-mt-victoria-m1-palmerston-kumeti-doc-campsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 01:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-270-4613km-to-4845km-3713-friday-10th-june-mt-victoria-m1-palmerston-kumeti-doc-campsite/</guid>
      <description>Wellington is lush in the sun. That was yesterday. Today it is peeing it down and is misty and miserable. Although it still is a lovely city, it’s difficult to be positive when it’s bad bad weather.
Drove up to Mt Victoria after a detour around the coastline where we spotted a few personal cable cars including the one we’d seen modelled in the Cable Car museum. Your own cable car, how cool would that be?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 269 (4598km to 4612km 36/14) Thursday 9th June – Wellington</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-269-4598km-to-4612km-3614-thursday-9th-june-wellington/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2011 01:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/10/day-269-4598km-to-4612km-3614-thursday-9th-june-wellington/</guid>
      <description>Found a great place to park up the campervan smack in the centre of Wellington harbour-side. It’s basically a carpark but there are spaces for motorhomes for which you pay $50 per 24hr period and there are even keypad entry loos and showers. Might be a good business idea for any big city in the UK 😉
This meant we could park up all day to explore Wellington, have a couple of drinks and an evening out and come back to the van to sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 268 (4400 to to 4580 to 4597km 35/15) Wednesday 8th June – Picton &amp; Marlborough Sound to Wellington, North Island</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/07/day-268-4400-to-to-4580-to-4597km-3515-wednesday-8th-june-picton-marlborough-sound-to-wellington-north-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 03:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/07/day-268-4400-to-to-4580-to-4597km-3515-wednesday-8th-june-picton-marlborough-sound-to-wellington-north-island/</guid>
      <description>After 5 weeks in the South Island we’re off to the North and the capital of NZ. Right now I’m sat on the Interislander ferry from Picton to Wellington with fabulous views out of the window of Marlborough Sounds. It’s a far better ferry than the ones I remember going on student exchange trips to Germany. I don’t feel seasick for one thing.
Arrived early (for us) in Picton so we could explore Queen Charlotte Drive, the slow winding extremely scenic road with some parts falling into the sea between Picton and Havelock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 267 (4030km to 4399km 34/16) Tuesday 7th June – back to Christchurch &amp; back to Okiwi Bay, Kaikoura</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/07/day-267-4030km-to-4399km-3416-tuesday-7th-june-back-to-christchurch-back-to-okiwi-bay-kaikoura/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 02:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/07/day-267-4030km-to-4399km-3416-tuesday-7th-june-back-to-christchurch-back-to-okiwi-bay-kaikoura/</guid>
      <description>Today’s weather: improved, some blue sky. No rain.
Drove around the Banks Peninsula bays of Baron Bay and Okains Bay. Two secluded beaches with not a soul but us. Sometimes this travelling at off-peak really has its benefits. This took us along the tourist drive on the summit of the peninsula so you could really see how this area used to be volcanoes. Again stunning scenery.
Baron BayOkains BayStopped for a spot of lunch in a teeny bay I can’t remember the name of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 266 (3787km to 4029km 33/17) Monday 6th June – Akaroa</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/07/day-266-3787km-to-4029km-3317-monday-6th-june-akaroa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 02:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/07/day-266-3787km-to-4029km-3317-monday-6th-june-akaroa/</guid>
      <description>It’s a bank holiday in NZ today for the Queen’s birthday.
5.5 aftershock whilst in Timaru. Matt was in the van and felt it shake for 30 seconds. I was in the shower block and felt nothing. Apparently the epicentre was 40km south-west of Christchurch. We’re heading in that direction today. Some damage to buildings and roads reported.
Passed over the longest bridge in New Zealand. Enough said about that. That’s all I can say anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 265 cont…  Moeraki boulders</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/07/day-265-cont-moeraki-boulders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 02:51:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/07/07/day-265-cont-moeraki-boulders/</guid>
      <description>Almost forgot to say about the Moeraki boulders. How could I forget? A strange phenomenon on a beach in a small place called Moeraki just south of Oamaru. A kind of stop for 5 minutes if you’re passing type of place.
Here’s the obligatory silly photo of Karen, this time with her over-sized white trainers on (the only “sensible” shoes I have on this trip).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 265 (3565km to 3786km 32/18) – Sunday 5th June – Oamaru &amp; Timaru</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/23/day-265-3565km-to-3786km-3218-sunday-5th-june-oamaru-timaru/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 09:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/23/day-265-3565km-to-3786km-3218-sunday-5th-june-oamaru-timaru/</guid>
      <description>Fish &amp;amp; chips by the sea at Oamaru. Our first in NZ. Lip-smackingly tasty freshly battered elephant fish &amp;amp; sole.
Tried to see some more penguins but we had arrived too early in the day and as we needed to gain more ground north continued our road trip to a holiday park in Timaru which was owned by a nice man from Nottingham whom had emigrated here 10 years ago when the exchange rate was NZ$3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 263 &amp; 264 (3428km to 3564km) Friday 3rd &amp; Saturday 4th June – Dunedin</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-263-264-3428km-to-3564km-friday-3rd-saturday-4th-june-dunedin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 13:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-263-264-3428km-to-3564km-friday-3rd-saturday-4th-june-dunedin/</guid>
      <description>I am writing two days together as they have events that bleed from one day to the next.
The drive from Kaka Point to Dunedin was non-descript.
Dunedin on the other hand has been colourful to say the least.
There are no holiday parks in the centre so we decided to go for a cheap backpackers called Pennys 5 mins walk from The Octagon (city centre). They had one double room left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 262 (3145km to 3427km 29/21) Thursday 2nd June – Bluff to two Southern points of NZ to one yellow-eyed penguin to Kaka Point campsite</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-262-3145km-to-3427km-2921-thursday-2nd-june-bluff-to-two-southern-points-of-nz-to-one-yellow-eyed-penguin-to-kaka-point-campsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 13:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-262-3145km-to-3427km-2921-thursday-2nd-june-bluff-to-two-southern-points-of-nz-to-one-yellow-eyed-penguin-to-kaka-point-campsite/</guid>
      <description>Matt invented a game to stop the driving boredom – beep the sheep. Every field of sheep we went past he would slow down and beep his horn. Very irresponsible but pretty funny as all sheep in the vicinity would perk their heads up in fear and then leg it. It doesn’t work as well for cows. They just don’t care enough for beeping and carry on chewing the cud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 261 (2882km to 3144km 28/22) Wednesday 1st June – Te Anau, Manapouri, Suspension Bridge, Invercargill</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-261-2882km-to-3144km-2822-wednesday-1st-june-te-anau-manapouri-suspension-bridge-invercargill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 12:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-261-2882km-to-3144km-2822-wednesday-1st-june-te-anau-manapouri-suspension-bridge-invercargill/</guid>
      <description>The sun is shining today, the blue skies are back. Darn it. Should we have stayed in Milford Sound? But you looked so miserable yesterday MS!
Breakfast views at Mackay CreekStill it made for some beautiful lake views in Te Anau and Manapouri.
Te AnauManapouri
The route to Invercargill believe it or not included a stop at Clifton suspension bridge. We were back in Bristol. Ah my mistake it was Clifden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 260 (2715km to 2881km 27/23) Tuesday 31st May – Milford Sound and back again</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-260-2715km-to-2881km-2723-tuesday-31st-may-milford-sound-and-back-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 12:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-260-2715km-to-2881km-2723-tuesday-31st-may-milford-sound-and-back-again/</guid>
      <description>So this is where we camped last night.Our jamminess ran out today. Weather was extremely RUBBISH for going to Milford Sound. Rain &amp;amp; fog are not conducive to picturesque views across sea and mountains. But hey you can’t win ‘em all.
The drive to Milford Sound was pretty spectacular despite the sh*tty weather. You could still get the gist of it and there were definitely Misty Mountains galore.
The most exciting bit of the trip there was the 1km tunnel bored straight through a mountain which was practically pitch black and coming out of the other end into the light you were faced with a sheer drop surrounded by overbearing mountains and an Italian-countryside-Formula-one-esque hairpin road downwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 259 (2499km to 2714km 26/24) Monday 30th May – Queenstown to Henry’s Creek nr Te Anau</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-259-2499km-to-2714km-2624-monday-30th-may-queenstown-to-henrys-creek-nr-te-anau/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 11:34:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/22/day-259-2499km-to-2714km-2624-monday-30th-may-queenstown-to-henrys-creek-nr-te-anau/</guid>
      <description>Not satisfied with our adrenaline-filled Sunday we went on the Shotover Jet today. A 30min jet-powered speedboat ride through shallow water, down narrow canyons and 360° spins. Pretty exciting but not as good as the bungy. We’re thinking we should have done them the other way around.
Walked, &amp;amp; climbed in part, up to top of hill (Ben Lomond national park) behind Queenstown to see more stunning views.
Took the Gondola back down the hill and reluctantly left Queenstown to drive to a campsite north of Te Anau halfway to Milford Sound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 258 (2498km 25/25) Sunday 29th May – Queenstown – Nevis highwire 134m bungy</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-258-2498km-2525-sunday-29th-may-queenstown-nevis-highwire-134m-bungy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 09:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-258-2498km-2525-sunday-29th-may-queenstown-nevis-highwire-134m-bungy/</guid>
      <description>OH MY GOD! Matt &amp;amp; I did a 134m bungy jump today. It was incredible!
Stupidly booked it for the afternoon so we both spent the morning sweating about it when all we wanted to do was get it over and done with.
It was also a 45min drive out of town so our 2 o’clock appt was just for the bus ride.
You get your full-body harness on and go on a open cable car across the canyon to the bungy car hanging over a massive canyon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 257 (2493km to 2498km 24/26) Saturday 28th May –Queenstown</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-257-2493km-to-2498km-2426-saturday-28th-may-queenstown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-257-2493km-to-2498km-2426-saturday-28th-may-queenstown/</guid>
      <description>Feeling a little worse for wear. Our lush view from our campervan was lost on us.
Managed to get enough energy to move to the holiday park in town as we know we want to stay in QT a couple more days.
I’m sure we must still be drunk though as just gone and booked a bungy jump for tomorrow. Arghhh!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 256 (2414km to 2492km 23/27) Friday 27th May – Queenstown</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-256-2414km-to-2492km-2327-friday-27th-may-queenstown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 09:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-256-2414km-to-2492km-2327-friday-27th-may-queenstown/</guid>
      <description>Random photos taken before leaving Wanaka.This one was taken by Matt after he turned the van around on a busy main road to specifically to this field of sheep, parked up, ran across the road, tried jumping over a ditch and promptly sprained his ankle. Any excuse not to drive. Stunning views on the road from Wanaka to Queenstown. Queenstown is in a beautiful setting on Lake Wakatipu surrounded by snow-capped mountains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 255 (2414km 22/28) Thursday 26th May – Wanaka</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-255-2414km-2228-thursday-26th-may-wanaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 09:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-255-2414km-2228-thursday-26th-may-wanaka/</guid>
      <description>Here we go again. Another bad weather day.
Stayed in our van on our deserted campsite watching the clouds float across the hills working on SCF.
Didn’t do anything really all day except a half hour walk to the lake and back via New World supermarket. Fun stuff.
Ever heard of a battered lasagne? No, nor us. They sell them in New World. Taste like a deep-fried lasagne, bizarrely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 254 (2356km to 2413km 21/29) Wednesday 25th May – Wanaka</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-254-2356km-to-2413km-2129-wednesday-25th-may-wanaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 09:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-254-2356km-to-2413km-2129-wednesday-25th-may-wanaka/</guid>
      <description>Hell of a night being bashed around by stormy weather then gorgeous morning with the view we were hoping for. Pipping those Wicked campervans to the post for this spot on this tiny DOC island was worth the under-their-breath cussing we probably got from them.
Travelled to Wanaka passing more lovely things.We fell in love with Wanaka immediately and may stay another day or 2 or 3…
It has that alpine village feel set on a beautiful lakeside and surrounded by mountains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 253 (2190km to 2355km 20/30) Tuesday 24th May – Haast, Thunder Creek Falls &amp; Boundary Creek campsite</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-253-2190km-to-2355km-2030-tuesday-24th-may-haast-thunder-creek-falls-boundary-creek-campsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 08:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-253-2190km-to-2355km-2030-tuesday-24th-may-haast-thunder-creek-falls-boundary-creek-campsite/</guid>
      <description>Non-eventful day.
Woke up, it was raining. Run was pointless. Nowhere to run to except around the carpark 4 times getting wet.
Stayed in all morning blogging &amp;amp; working on SCF. It rained some more.
Drove to Haast. Grey, depressing place in winter. The cheapest tin of baked beans in their only shop was $2. Wanted fish &amp;amp; chips but couldn’t bring ourselves to try the bleak cafe. Stubbornly ate pasta-in-sauce on the side of the road whilst it drizzled and continued on our way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 252 (2078km to 2189km 19/31) Monday 23rd May – Fox Glacier &amp; Lake Bazinga</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-252-2078km-to-2189km-1931-monday-23rd-may-fox-glacier-lake-bazinga/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 07:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-252-2078km-to-2189km-1931-monday-23rd-may-fox-glacier-lake-bazinga/</guid>
      <description>Brekkie today was in our own private holiday park with a backdrop of forested hills and snowy mountains.
Mostly a day of working on SCF in the campervan sat outside a nearby backpackers lodge which had wifi with our chosen provider. We are very sad. But hey there’s work to be done.
A whistle-stop trip to Fox Glacier. It was cold and rainy and low cloud cloaked the hills. Very a la Misty Mountains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 251 (2052km to 2077 18/32) Sunday 22nd May – Franz Josef helicopters &amp; glaciers</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-251-2052km-to-2077-1832-sunday-22nd-may-franz-josef-helicopters-glaciers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 07:09:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/16/day-251-2052km-to-2077-1832-sunday-22nd-may-franz-josef-helicopters-glaciers/</guid>
      <description>Woke up this morning planning to do a Heli-hike. 10 min helicopter ride followed by 2hr glacier hike and 10min helicopter ride back. It was bland weather. Grey, overcast and chilly. And when we thought about it $400 each was a bit steep. So perhaps we just walk today and then see what the weather’s like in Fox Glacier tomorrow?
Well by the time we’d faffed about waking up and all that jazz and then watched huge trout jump around in the shallow river trying to get up stream, the sun was itching to come out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for better low-light wedding photos with a Canon DSLR.</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/06/14/tips-for-better-low-light-wedding-photos-with-an-canon-dslr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 05:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/06/14/tips-for-better-low-light-wedding-photos-with-an-canon-dslr/</guid>
      <description>I just got this in an email:
 A friend has asked me to take some of their wedding photos with their Canon 1000D. Had a play with it yesterday and I’m finding the flash a bit harsh. Is there a top tip to minimise this?
 Firstly, if you’re using the camera in the day near natural light, the camera will be fine and it’s all down to your artistic flair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 250 (1876km to 2051km 17/33) Saturday 21st May – Hokitika to Franz Josef</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/11/day-250-1876km-to-2051km-1733-saturday-21st-may-hokitika-to-franz-josef/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 06:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/11/day-250-1876km-to-2051km-1733-saturday-21st-may-hokitika-to-franz-josef/</guid>
      <description>Firstly Happy Birthday to Tony, again. Sorry we sent you your birthday card a month early and sorry this message will be very belated as I am so behind on my blogs we probably will be back home before you get to read this. Hope you had a good one.
We had a pleasant day celebrating Tony’s birthday, our 250th day on the road and over 2000km travelled in NZ. Began with brekkie by Lake Mahinapua.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 249 (1695km to 1875km 16/34) Friday 20th May – Westport to Greymouth to Hokitika</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/11/day-249-1695km-to-1875km-1634-friday-20th-may-westport-to-greymouth-to-hokitika/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 06:09:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/11/day-249-1695km-to-1875km-1634-friday-20th-may-westport-to-greymouth-to-hokitika/</guid>
      <description>Miserable weather today. Drizzling and grey. It’s like being back in the UK. The weather cannot make up its mind. Except that, unlike the UK in winter, when it’s sunny it’s hot.
1696 to 1824km Westport to Greymouth
Drove to Cape Foulwind where you can walk 4km to the Seal Colony. Ambled to a boring lighthouse and back which took us at least 10 mins and watched some what we thought might be Kiwis (type: bird) but are in fact Wekas (have more recently found out that Kiwis are really rare) fighting over bread I threw for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 248 (1422km to 1694km 15/35) Thursday 19th May – Nelson to Westport</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/05/day-248-1422km-to-1694km-1535-thursday-19th-may-nelson-to-westport/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 06:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/05/day-248-1422km-to-1694km-1535-thursday-19th-may-nelson-to-westport/</guid>
      <description>1422 to 1531km
Left the Nelson I-Site carpark early again to land at Lake Rotoroa for brekkie overlooking lake &amp;amp; mountains.
1532 to 1694km
The road to Westport through Buller’s Gorge was another impressive route.
Stopped off at “Buller’s Swingbridge”. The longest swingbridge in NZ. You pay $5 to cross it and can pay lots more to take a “Flying Fox” back across. The wire swingbridge is across a wide river full of rapids and is quite good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 247 (1230km to 1421km 14/36) Wednesday 18th May – Takaka to Totaranui to Nelson</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/05/day-247-1230km-to-1421km-1436-wednesday-18th-may-takaka-to-totaranui-to-nelson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 06:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/05/day-247-1230km-to-1421km-1436-wednesday-18th-may-takaka-to-totaranui-to-nelson/</guid>
      <description>Gave Matt a break from driving and I did it all today. Why I chose the one day we had to drive 10km on gravel track 1.5 cars wide is beyond me. Still we survived.
Left our exciting car park nice and early (well 7:30) to go to Totaranui beach at the north-western tip of the Abel Tasman national park. Because it was an unsealed road for 10km it took bloody ages and wound round and round, left and right up and down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 246 (1097km to 1229km 13/37) Tuesday 17th May – Nelson to Marahau to Takaka</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/05/day-246-1097km-to-1229km-1337-tuesday-17th-may-nelson-to-marahau-to-takaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 05:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/05/day-246-1097km-to-1229km-1337-tuesday-17th-may-nelson-to-marahau-to-takaka/</guid>
      <description>1097km to 1164km Nelson to Marahau
Sometimes we can be so jammy. We left Nelson at 8:10 to go to Marahau not knowing how long it would take hoping we could get the 9:30 Aqua taxi to Anchorage to do a 4 hour walk along the coast of the Abel Tasman National Park. We arrived in their car park at 9:15, Matt bought the last 2 tickets whilst I stuffed our bags with warm clothing, waterproofs and random food for the trip and jumped straight on the boat (on the back of a tractor/trailer) into the best seats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 245 (1031km to 1096km 12/38) Monday 16th May – Nelson &amp; the centre of NZ</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/05/day-245-1031km-to-1096km-1238-monday-16th-may-nelson-the-centre-of-nz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2011 05:39:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/05/day-245-1031km-to-1096km-1238-monday-16th-may-nelson-the-centre-of-nz/</guid>
      <description>Had plans to got to Abel Tasman today but spent all day in Nelson. Somehow the day just flew by. Mainly me faffing about trying to use wifi to upload blogs. Well I have been very slack recently.
3 hours later wandered around town which was pretty bland although the Currywurst &amp;amp; Kranksy were delicious. Who would have thought you could buy good German sausage in NZ?
Our daily exercise consisted of a short hike up a hill to the centre of NZ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 244 (977km to 1030km 11/39) – Sunday 15th May – Havelock greenshell mussels &amp; Pelorus Bridge</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/03/day-244-977km-to-1030-1139-sunday-15th-may-havelock-greenshell-mussels-pelorus-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 04:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/03/day-244-977km-to-1030-1139-sunday-15th-may-havelock-greenshell-mussels-pelorus-bridge/</guid>
      <description>Left Renwick and landed in Havelock 30mins later in the rain so sat at the harbourside until lunchtime watching the clouds pass over the hills and the rainbows fade in and out, in and out.
Lunch at the Mussel Pot for famous huge Havelock greenshell mussels in a blue-cheese sauce and blue-cheese mussel chowder. (Hmm seem to be hooked on blue-cheese?)
Only managed to get a bit further up the road to pitch in Pelorus Bridge, a DOC campsite in the forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 243 (961km to 977km 10/40) – Saturday 14th May – Renwick – wine-tasting by tandem</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/03/day-243-961km-to-977km-1040-saturday-14th-may-renwick-wine-tasting-tandem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 04:10:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/03/day-243-961km-to-977km-1040-saturday-14th-may-renwick-wine-tasting-tandem/</guid>
      <description>It’s sunny again. Hooray! So back to Renwick we trot, jump on a tandem bike (a first for both of us) and off round the vineyards we toddle.
1st stop: Forrest wines. We have a voucher for a free tasting tray from our kind bike hire guy at Old Mill B&amp;amp;B. Unfortunately just moments before arriving my trouser leg becomes trapped in the bike chain and rips half the hem off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 242 (930km to 960km 9/41) – Friday 13th May – Blenheim Top 10 Holiday park</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/03/day-242-930km-to-960km-941-friday-13th-may-blenheim-top-10-holiday-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 03:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/03/day-242-930km-to-960km-941-friday-13th-may-blenheim-top-10-holiday-park/</guid>
      <description>Wake up in the Cork &amp;amp; Keg carpark with rain battering on the windows. Darn it. No wine tour for us today.
We go back to Blenheim, find a powered campsite next to a river, invest in wifi and hole up for the day working on SCF.
People are still tweeting about it 17 days after the initial blogging and it’s appearing on so many different websites and in many different languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 241 (786km to 929km 8/42) Thursday 12th May – Blenheim &amp; Renwick</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/03/day-241-786km-to-929km-842-thursday-12th-may-blenheim-renwick/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 02:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/06/03/day-241-786km-to-929km-842-thursday-12th-may-blenheim-renwick/</guid>
      <description>Another glorious day to wake up to. The van was like a greenhouse. Lovely waking up being all toasty.
I ran across the railway line and along the beachside for a different perspective of Okiwi Bay. After yesterday’s walk the legs were a tad sore but it feels good to actually be active again (even if it is only for 10mins each day).
Our drive took us north to Blenheim in Marlborough County.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 240 (702km to 785km 7/43) Wednesday 11th May – Kaikoura – Okiwi Bay &amp; Peninsula walk</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/26/day-240-702km-to-785km-743-wednesday-11th-may-kaikoura-okiwi-bay-peninsula-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 12:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/26/day-240-702km-to-785km-743-wednesday-11th-may-kaikoura-okiwi-bay-peninsula-walk/</guid>
      <description>Woken up by the sun beaming through the curtains. Dragged Matt out for a run too and he sped off ahead of me uphill to Okiwi lookout. Stunning views of the sea, train track &amp;amp; our little van the only vehicle in the campsite. It was knackering.
Popped across the road to have breakfast with the back doors open over the sea.
The drive back to Kaikoura was a completely different story from the drive out to the campsite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 239 (513km to 701km 6/44) – Tuesday 10th May – Hanmer Springs to Kaikoura</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/26/day-239-513km-to-701km-644-tuesday-10th-may-hanmer-springs-to-kaikoura/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 10:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/26/day-239-513km-to-701km-644-tuesday-10th-may-hanmer-springs-to-kaikoura/</guid>
      <description>Groundhog day.
Woke up at the same campsite, did another 10 minute run and sat outside the library using the free wifi. What an exciting life we are leading.
Better than working.
SCF is really taking off and Matt has had more journalists contacting him. One from the BBC online Technology section today. Yesterday it was the Guardian newspaper. And to top it off he was on BBC Lincolnshire last night so we listened to the clip they’d sent him and laughed and learned a few things about radio shows :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kuala Lumpur Petronas Towers sunset timelapse</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/26/kuala-lumpur-petronas-towers-sunset-timelapse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 23:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/26/kuala-lumpur-petronas-towers-sunset-timelapse/</guid>
      <description>No we’re not back in Kuala Lumpur. Matt has found a spare 5 mins for creating time-lapsing goodness.
Here’s one from the Skybar, Trader’s Hotel at sunset.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 238 (501km to 512km 5/45) – Monday 9th May – Hanmer Springs – Conical Hill Walk</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-238-501km-to-512km-545-monday-9th-may-hanmer-springs-conical-hill-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 05:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-238-501km-to-512km-545-monday-9th-may-hanmer-springs-conical-hill-walk/</guid>
      <description>Kelloggs sunshine breakfast. A beautiful day and a beautiful walk up Conical Hill to 560m with 360 degree view across Hurunui.
And gnome-friendly funghi. We’d been without wifi for 2 days and the withdrawal symptoms were showing. As luck would have it the local library has wifi so we parked up outside to get our free fix. 4 hours later and laptop batteries dead we realise we missed our opportunity to drive to Kaikoura and have ended up back at Alpine holiday park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 237 (381km to 500km 4/46) – Sunday 8th May – Hanmer Springs</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-237-381km-to-500km-446-sunday-8th-may-hanmer-springs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-237-381km-to-500km-446-sunday-8th-may-hanmer-springs/</guid>
      <description>We can’t believe how much water we use and how much waste we make. This is an eye-opener. We have no more water again and we need to empty everything. Our tank holds 91 litres and apparently the shower uses 10 litres a minute. Can’t quite believe it.
Shared the driving today. A little scary at first on the winding roads after 8 months of no driving but it was like riding a bike and I soon got back into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 236 (166km to 380km 3/47) – Saturday 7th May – Mt Thomas Forest to Kaiapoi to Deer Valley, Lewis Pass</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-236-166km-to-380km-347-saturday-7th-may-mt-thomas-forest-to-kaiapoi-to-deer-valley-lewis-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 05:08:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-236-166km-to-380km-347-saturday-7th-may-mt-thomas-forest-to-kaiapoi-to-deer-valley-lewis-pass/</guid>
      <description>That muddy field we were in had increased in bogginess overnight and also half-filled with anorak-covered people putting up tents whilst we were eating brekkie which meant fun for us getting out. We discovered today that our campervan doesn’t have great traction so we slid about all over the place trying to manoeuvre around tents, cars &amp;amp; vans to just about get out safely.
We also discovered that although we thought the grey water indicator wasn’t working it in fact is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 235 (0km to 165km 2/48) – Friday 6th May – Christchurch to Wooded Gully campsite &amp; getting lost a lot</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-235-0km-to-165km-248-friday-6th-may-christchurch-to-wooded-gully-campsite-getting-lost-a-lot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 05:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-235-0km-to-165km-248-friday-6th-may-christchurch-to-wooded-gully-campsite-getting-lost-a-lot/</guid>
      <description>It’s raining. Quick trip to Spencer Beach to see the sea &amp;amp; sand minus sun.
Found the Department of Conservation (DOC) centre after our 2nd attempt to arm ourselves with a list of the DOC campsites across New Zealand which are much cheaper than commercial sites or even free.
Went in search of the first motorhome dumpstation getting lost a couple of times circling Christchurch. The not so glorious side of campervanning is getting rid of waste water and filling up with new water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 234 (0km 1/49) – Thursday 5th May – First day of campervanning around New Zealand (practice run)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-234-0km-149-thursday-5th-may-first-day-of-campervanning-around-new-zealand-practice-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 04:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-234-0km-149-thursday-5th-may-first-day-of-campervanning-around-new-zealand-practice-run/</guid>
      <description>First aftershock felt this morning at the hostel. I was sat checking my email and Matt was coming out of the shower. It felt really surreal. Everything seemed to shudder but you couldn’t put your finger on what moved or even if you moved. The sound was like someone running across a landing with hobnail boots on but we were on the ground floor. The adrenaline pumped for a few minutes afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 233 – Wednesday 4th May – Christchurch</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-233-wednesday-4th-may-christchurch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 04:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-233-wednesday-4th-may-christchurch/</guid>
      <description>Mmmm beans on toast. Lush.
Booked our campervan. Have opted for the posh option because we’re old fogies and would kill each other being cramped into a VW with only enough headspace for a hobbit.
SCF update: 280,000 unique visitors in the past week. That is an 35,600% increase!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 232 – Tuesday 3rd May – Christchurch, New Zealand</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-232-tuesday-3rd-may-christchurch-new-zealand/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 04:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/25/day-232-tuesday-3rd-may-christchurch-new-zealand/</guid>
      <description>Qantas again delivered. Both the Bangkok to Sydney and the Sydney to Christchurch legs were on time and well fed. Had about 6 meals in 12 hours as our clocks turned forward 3 hours then another 2. We’re a total of 11 hours ahead of the UK now so when you’re waking up to eat your cornflakes we’ll be finishing dinner and off to bed.
Look Australia! Arriving at Christchurch airport customs we were scared into throwing our packet of crisps into the bin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 228 to 231 – Friday 29th April to Monday 2nd May – Siem Reap to Bangkok to New Zealand – surviving Poipet again &amp; Chatuchak weekend market</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/19/day-228-to-231-friday-29th-april-to-monday-2nd-may-siem-reap-to-bangkok-to-new-zealand-surviving-poipet-again-chatuchak-weekend-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 06:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/19/day-228-to-231-friday-29th-april-to-monday-2nd-may-siem-reap-to-bangkok-to-new-zealand-surviving-poipet-again-chatuchak-weekend-market/</guid>
      <description>We thought our 10.5hr journey Battambang to Bangkok and 11.5hr trip back from Bangkok to Siem Reap were the norm travel times between Thailand and Cambodia. Not when you have a Michael Schumacher wannabe behind the wheel of the Thai minibus. Our coach left Siem Reap at 8.15 (with Matt sat in the guide’s seat as they seemed to have run out of usual passenger seats by the time we were told it was OK to board) and after 2 pointless stops we were at the border at 11:30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 224 to 227 cont…</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/19/day-224-to-227-cont/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 06:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/19/day-224-to-227-cont/</guid>
      <description>Outside of class we only actually went and did something other than eat &amp;amp; sleep. We went shopping! They have a night market with so many lovely stalls selling souvenirs, clothes and jewellery and a very cool domed bar/restaurant in the centre. Needless to say I re-filled another bag to replace the one Wendy &amp;amp; Steve had kindly taken home for us. And bought a gorgeous silver ring typically on the day that silver was at an all time high so they were reluctant to barter or even sell it to me at one point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 224 to 227 – Monday 25th to Thursday 28th April – 2nd week teaching at SHAC</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/19/day-224-to-227-monday-25th-to-thursday-28th-april-2nd-week-teaching-at-shac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 06:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/19/day-224-to-227-monday-25th-to-thursday-28th-april-2nd-week-teaching-at-shac/</guid>
      <description>Monday back to school and whilst UK basks in hot sunny weather on a bank holiday we get rain so the cycle there is nice and muddy. It’s a little like being back at home except it’s still roasting.
Aly had some bad news. During the storm on Saturday the lightning had struck everyone’s homes in the area killing everyone’s TVs, her stereo, modem and her husband’s PC. There is a phone mast just next door and so it must have attracted the lightning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 223 – Sunday 23rd April – Samoeun’s family &amp; party</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-223-sunday-23rd-april-samoeuns-family-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 01:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-223-sunday-23rd-april-samoeuns-family-party/</guid>
      <description>Sunday was party day at Samoeun’s house. He works at Palm Garden Lodge and had invited us a few days ago. He was providing the food and we’d provide the beer.
At 3:30 when Samoeun finished work he took us off in his friend’s tuk-tuk to his home in another village on the outskirts of Siem Reap near West Baray. Stopped off on the way for a couple of crates of beer and a block of ice in a carrier bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 222 – Saturday 22nd April – another side to Siem Reap</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-222-saturday-22nd-april-another-side-to-siem-reap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 01:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-222-saturday-22nd-april-another-side-to-siem-reap/</guid>
      <description>Saturday I went off for the morning with Aly to what I thought was advertising her charity in town. But when she said into town she didn’t mean Siem Reap. To her that is the city. A town is a smaller place west of Siem reap on the outskirts called ???? which in English means “Basket”.
So I hopped on the back of her moped and away we went.
She introduced me to some of the families who weave baskets in this area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 217 to 221 – Monday 18th to Friday 22nd April – Siem Reap – week 1 of English teaching at shac-smilinghearts</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-217-to-221-monday-18th-to-friday-22nd-april-siem-reap-week-1-of-english-teaching-at-shac-smilinghearts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 01:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-217-to-221-monday-18th-to-friday-22nd-april-siem-reap-week-1-of-english-teaching-at-shac-smilinghearts/</guid>
      <description>I have been teaching every day from 9:30 to 11:30 and from 15:30 to 17:30 at the shac-smilinghearts school set up by Aly which opened on November 1st 2010. I cycle there and back twice a day. It’s only just over 1km away down mud tracks, past a mixture of large houses and small wooden houses on stilts. Men &amp;amp; boys sit at the side of the polluted streams that run through the village with their fishing rods hoping to catch something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 209 to 216 – Sunday 10th to Sunday 17th April – Siem Reap</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-209-to-216-sunday-10th-to-sunday-17th-april-siem-reap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 01:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-209-to-216-sunday-10th-to-sunday-17th-april-siem-reap/</guid>
      <description>We’re suffering from too much chill-out time, are feeling too de-stressed and need to take a break from the travelling so have come back to Siem Reap for three weeks off to work on stolencamerafinder.
Only when we get here do we remember that the LP describes April in Cambodia as the “killer month”. They weren’t wrong.
Sunday was hot.
Monday was hotter. Blue skies, glaring sunshine. We had our 1st beer after 2 days dry since seeing Wend &amp;amp; Steve in Bangkok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 208 Saturday 9th April – Bangkok to Siem Reap overland via Poipet (train &amp; bus)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-208-saturday-9th-april-bangkok-to-siem-reap-overland-via-poipet-train-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-208-saturday-9th-april-bangkok-to-siem-reap-overland-via-poipet-train-bus/</guid>
      <description>Never get the train from Bangkok to Aranya Prathet (border).
2 hours on a hard upright seat from Bangkok to Ayuthaya at lunchtime is fine. It’s doable.
6 hours plus half hour delay starting at 6am when you’re knackered because you didn’t sleep properly the night before is uncomfortable to say the least.
The train was relatively empty when we left Hualamphong station. We had a 3-seater for the two of us so nodding off was not a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 206 &amp; 207 – Thursday 7th &amp; Friday 8th April – Bangkok – Wendy &amp; Steve are back</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-206-207-thursday-7th-friday-8th-april-bangkok-wendy-steve-are-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-206-207-thursday-7th-friday-8th-april-bangkok-wendy-steve-are-back/</guid>
      <description>Wendy &amp;amp; Steve are coming back today and they’re staying in Khao San Road. Bugger. Ah well it’s not that far from Silom. Maybe 7km.
We aim to get a boat to KSR to meet them but are running late as usual so head over in a taxi. The traffic is a nightmare. It’s peak-time so takes 50mins. By the time we get there they’re already on their 2nd beer. And it goes downhill from then on really.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 198 to 205 – Wednesday 30th March to Wednesday 6th April – Bangkok in limbo</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-198-to-205-wednesday-30th-march-to-wednesday-6th-april-bangkok-in-limbo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:33:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/16/day-198-to-205-wednesday-30th-march-to-wednesday-6th-april-bangkok-in-limbo/</guid>
      <description>Not sure why exactly but we stayed in Bangkok until Wendy came back.
We had wanted to go to the coast but with the weather being so terrible we didn’t want to risk it. And with Matt keen to get on with www.stolencamerafinder.com we pottered about doing not much at all except that.
Wednesday night we tried a kooky restaurant called Cabbages &amp;amp; Condoms in Sukhumvit. It’s a restaurant that gives some of its profits to HIV/AIDS charities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 195 to 197 – Sunday 27th to Tuesday 29th March – Bangkok – Wendy &amp; Steve arrive!</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/13/please-check-photos-day-195-to-197-sunday-27th-to-tuesday-29th-march-bangkok-wendy-steve-arrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 02:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/13/please-check-photos-day-195-to-197-sunday-27th-to-tuesday-29th-march-bangkok-wendy-steve-arrive/</guid>
      <description>Sunday we checked out of Sunflower Place and into Siam Heritage kindly paid for by W &amp;amp; S for our joint birthday pressies. What a place. So swanky. I’m going to sound like a complete child now but it had proper porters take our luggage to the room on one of those brass wheelie things. The bed is huge! The desk has one of those green lamps on it. There are satin dressing gowns and slippers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 194 – Saturday 26 March – Battambang to Bangkok – crossing the Cambodian/Thai border at Poipet</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/10/day-194-saturday-26-march-battambang-to-bangkok-crossing-the-cambodianthai-border-at-poipet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/10/day-194-saturday-26-march-battambang-to-bangkok-crossing-the-cambodianthai-border-at-poipet/</guid>
      <description>We’re off to meet up with Wend &amp;amp; Steve in Bangkok. Given ourselves a day to get over the border so we get there in time!
Haha of the day: Matt tried to give some not quite so poor woman some money whilst she was just sat waiting for the bus. Much embarrassment.
The Poipet border crossing was quite painless. 20 mins queued up on Cambodia side to get our departure stamp followed by 30mins on the Thai border to be let in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 191 to 193 – Wednesday 23rd to Friday 25th March – Battambang – Bamboo train &amp; Cambodian cooking class</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/10/day-191-to-193-wednesday-23rd-to-friday-25th-march-battambang-bamboo-train-cambodian-cooking-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/10/day-191-to-193-wednesday-23rd-to-friday-25th-march-battambang-bamboo-train-cambodian-cooking-class/</guid>
      <description>Yes I was right. Hangovers from hell. I think we went to sleep about 5am and were up and out in the midday sun packed and waiting for a bus to Battambang. Not pretty.
Luckily the bus journey to Battambang was a bearable 3.5 hours. And trusting a tuk-tuk driver (Mr Bat from Battambang) at the bus stop paid off. The first hotel was full (an LP recommendation) so ended up at its sister hotel Asia Hotel a bit further away but one of the best places we’ve stayed in for comfort and cleanliness and wifi and a steal at $8 a night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 190 – Tuesday 22nd March – Siem Reap</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/09/day-190-tuesday-22nd-march-siem-reap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 03:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/09/day-190-tuesday-22nd-march-siem-reap/</guid>
      <description>After 2 days of temples we are all templed-out. We decide to spend the day doing not much.
So I decide to treat myself to a haircut. My first haircut in 7 months.
I drop by the local hairdressers. Not the one just outside Palm Garden Lodge (there were no customers and since going back in April it has turned into AB Bar with a red strip light and pretty ladyboys so probably wasn’t doing such a good job as a hair salon – this has no reflection on Palm Garden Lodge) but the one just down the road towards town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 189 – Monday 21st March – Siem Reap – The small circuit</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/09/day-189-monday-21st-april-siem-reap-the-small-circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 03:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/09/day-189-monday-21st-april-siem-reap-the-small-circuit/</guid>
      <description>5am start to Angkor Wat for sunrise. At that time of the morning Siem Reap is already humming with the sound of tuk-tuks, mopeds and bicycles all heading in one direction.
Making our way along the promenade we were stopped by ticket inspectors with torches before proceeding to join the hoards around the lake at the front of Angkor Wat. We managed to get a good seat on one of the small temples next to the lake and Matt set up his 7D for a timelapse that turned into a time lacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 188 – Sunday 20th March – Siem Reap – Angkor, The Big Circuit</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/09/day-188-sunday-20th-march-siem-reap-angkor-the-big-circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 03:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/05/09/day-188-sunday-20th-march-siem-reap-angkor-the-big-circuit/</guid>
      <description>We arrived early on Sunday morning being dropped off in a derelict backstreet yard. It was still dark so we could have been in Timbuktu for all we knew.
Luckily our guys at Palm Garden Lodge were awake and sent Mr. Long to meet us in his tuk tuk. 20 mins later we were snoozing in a lovely comfy room and 3 hours later we were eating noodle soup for breakfast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to update the lastmod date in your sitemap xml with Ant</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/04/22/how-to-update-the-lastmod-date-in-your-sitemap-xml-with-ant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 03:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/04/22/how-to-update-the-lastmod-date-in-your-sitemap-xml-with-ant/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, you want to add the “lastmod” node, but you’re too lazy to ever keep that up to date so you decide to update it with your Ant script whenever you deploy. Easy.
So you’ve just written a valid sitemap.xml file for your website because Google said it was a good idea. Great.
&amp;amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot; encoding=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot; standalone=&amp;quot;no&amp;quot;?&amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;lt;urlset xmlns=&amp;quot;http://www.sitemaps.org/schemas/sitemap/0.9&amp;quot;&amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;lt;url&amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;lt;loc&amp;amp;gt;http://www.stolencamerafinder.com/&amp;amp;lt;/loc&amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;lt;lastmod&amp;amp;gt;2011-04-21&amp;amp;lt;/lastmod&amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;lt;changefreq&amp;amp;gt;weekly&amp;amp;lt;/changefreq&amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;lt;/url&amp;amp;gt; &amp;amp;lt;/urlset&amp;amp;gt; First, you’ll need the jar for a third-party Ant task called XMLTask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to detect browser support for File Api and drag and drop with javascript</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/04/17/how-to-detect-browser-support-for-file-api-and-drag-and-drop-with-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 11:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/04/17/how-to-detect-browser-support-for-file-api-and-drag-and-drop-with-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a bit of info for you crazy HTML5 kids. You’ll need to include the handy Modernizr script for it to work.
var browserIsSupported = !!window.FileReader &amp;amp;&amp;amp; Modernizr.draganddrop; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find out your Facebook User ID (uid)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/04/17/how-to-find-out-your-facebook-user-id-uid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 04:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/04/17/how-to-find-out-your-facebook-user-id-uid/</guid>
      <description>Just look at the filename of your profile picture. The uid is in the middle.
186939_565140267_839650_n.jpg Er… That’s it.
Bye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halfway through! (Monday 14th March)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/14/halfway-through-monday-14th-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 03:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/14/halfway-through-monday-14th-march/</guid>
      <description>I only went and forgot to say in my blog on 14th March that we’re HALFWAY THROUGH! (well when we were in Phnom Penh we were and I can’t even remember what we did that day. I presume it involved one or two Angkor beers).
Funny how you can spend 10 years thinking about going travelling and here we are 50% done already.
6 months have flown by and from now on we’re on the way back….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 184 to 187 – Wednesday 16th to Saturday 19th March – Sihanoukville</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/13/day-184-to-187-wednesday-16th-to-saturday-19th-march-sihanoukville/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 05:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/13/day-184-to-187-wednesday-16th-to-saturday-19th-march-sihanoukville/</guid>
      <description>What do you do when you’re at the seaside? Go lie on the beach all day of course.
We hadn’t seen the sea since New Year in Thailand and it sounds sad but it was really exciting. Being by the Mekong is lovely but you just can’t beat seeing the sea stretch out to the horizon merging with the blue sky and the sound of waves on the sand. Lush.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 183 – Tuesday 15th March – Phnom Penh to Sihanoukville</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/13/day-183-tuesday-15th-march-phnom-penh-to-sihanoukville/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 05:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/13/day-183-tuesday-15th-march-phnom-penh-to-sihanoukville/</guid>
      <description>Our bus to Sihanoukville was booked for lunchtime so we thought we’d squeeze in some essential sight-seeing before we left Phnom Penh and visited the Royal Palace &amp;amp; Silver Pagoda first thing Tuesday morning. It took us less than an hour to be unimpressed by it. The Silver Pagoda is famed for its solid silver floor. We expected sparkling, dazzling. We got dull, scratched. Only a small amount was uncovered and “on display”, half of which was held down with masking tape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 179 to 182 – Friday 11th to Monday 14th March – Phnom Penh</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/13/day-179-to-182-friday-11th-to-monday-14th-march-phnom-penh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 04:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/13/day-179-to-182-friday-11th-to-monday-14th-march-phnom-penh/</guid>
      <description>I have been particularly slack on the blog writing front so am typing this a month after the event. Therefore it will be dry and sparse as my memory has faded and we have few photos.
From Sen Monorom we went to the capital Phnom Penh, on a normal bus, with one passenger per seat. It took 7 hours, less than we thought, and the journey went surprisingly fast.
By the time we’d settled into our hotel and ventured out it was dark so we couldn’t be bothered to explore too far for food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 175 to 178 – Monday 7th to Thursday 10th March – Sen Monorom, Mondulkiri province – 3 day elephant &amp; jungle trek</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/12/day-175-to-178-monday-7th-to-thursday-10th-march-sen-monorom-mondulkiri-province-3-day-elephant-jungle-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 05:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/12/day-175-to-178-monday-7th-to-thursday-10th-march-sen-monorom-mondulkiri-province-3-day-elephant-jungle-trek/</guid>
      <description>If we thought the journey from Stung Treng to Ban Lung was interesting it was nothing compared to the journey to Sen Monorom. How many people can you get in a 13 seater minivan? Well if you attach a luggage rack to the back (boot open), pack everyone’s belongings onto it, tie all the extra random bags full of random stuff around it and pile 4 people on top, 4 adults on each row of seats, 2 adults in the passenger seat and an extra passenger in the driver’s seat plus as many kids as there are gaps…about 26 plus driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 174 – Sunday 6th March – Kratie – Irawaddy dolphins</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/09/day-174-sunday-6th-march-kratie-irawaddy-dolphins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 15:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/09/day-174-sunday-6th-march-kratie-irawaddy-dolphins/</guid>
      <description>Kratie was a quiet town. Its main attraction, the rare freshwater Irawaddy dolphins, weren’t easy to spot as they tried their best to keep away from the 15 longtails rumbling around the Mekong close to sunset. However it was nice to see them as they could be extinct soon there are so few left.
Dolphins:And boats:

If you’re quick you may see one or two in these videos:
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 172 &amp; 173 – Friday 4th &amp; Saturday 5th March – Ban Lung, Ratanakiri province, Cambodia (Boeng Yeak Lom crater lake)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/09/day-172-173-friday-4th-saturday-5th-march-ban-lung-ratanakiri-province-cambodia-boeng-yeak-lom-crater-lake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 15:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/09/day-172-173-friday-4th-saturday-5th-march-ban-lung-ratanakiri-province-cambodia-boeng-yeak-lom-crater-lake/</guid>
      <description>Funny minivan journey with 16 adult passengers, 3 babies (one naked, one half-naked from the waist down) and an 8 year old carrying a small plastic bag that chirped. To get to Ban Lung in Ratanakiri province in the north east of Cambodia.
Found another form of paradise again in Tree Top Ecolodge. Very gorgeous wooden bungalows on stilts with all furniture made from reclaimed wood including a very simple but beautiful lamp which had a tree stump for a base and a branch for the stand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 171 – Thursday 3rd March – Laos to Cambodia – Stung Treng</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/09/day-171-thursday-3rd-march-laos-to-cambodia-stung-treng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 15:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/09/day-171-thursday-3rd-march-laos-to-cambodia-stung-treng/</guid>
      <description>After 6 weeks in Laos, we’re now in Cambodia!!
There’s Laos time and there’s snail time. It took us 5 hours to go approx 70km from Don Det to Stung Treng.
8am boat ride from Don Det to the mainland followed by a long wait on a dusty street outside a makeshift travel shop until 10am and we board a bus. Half hour or so later we’re at the Laos/Cambodia border.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to stop Google Chrome using your location when searching</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/04/08/how-to-stop-google-chrome-using-your-location-when-searching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2011 05:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2011/04/08/how-to-stop-google-chrome-using-your-location-when-searching/</guid>
      <description>When you use Chrome’s omnibar to search, Chrome will redirect you to search results based on when you are geographically. This is great when I’m at home because I see (more relevant) results from google.co.uk and not google.com.
However, I’m travelling at the moment and getting my results from google.co.th is painful since most of the results are not in english.
 Close Chrome. Open the file Local State in notepad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 170 – Wednesday 2nd March – Don Det &amp; Don Khon (Si Phan Don – 4000 islands)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/03/day-170-wednesday-2nd-march-don-det-don-khon-si-phan-don-4000-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 10:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/03/day-170-wednesday-2nd-march-don-det-don-khon-si-phan-don-4000-islands/</guid>
      <description>An hour and half longtail down the Mekong brought us to the island of Don Det. It’s the 4000 island’s answer to Vang Vieng as Don Khong is to Luang Prabang. Although both are on a much smaller scale there were the usual bedraggled hungover backpackers in their tubing vests, saggy hotpants and cigarettes hanging out their mouths loitering.
Can’t complain too much. Although our bungalow is basic and has a shared bathroom I am getting up-to-date with the blogs whilst lying in a hammock on the balcony with 180 degree views of the Mekong and across to Cambodia, and Matt’s snoozing in the hammock next to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 168 &amp; 169 – Monday 28th February to Tuesday 1st March – Don Khong (Si Phan Don – 4000 islands)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/03/day-168-169-monday-28th-february-to-tuesday-1st-march-don-khong-si-phan-don-4000-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 10:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/03/day-168-169-monday-28th-february-to-tuesday-1st-march-don-khong-si-phan-don-4000-islands/</guid>
      <description>Is it really March already? Unbelievable. Where does the time go when you’re having fun travelling around Asia?
Monday’s journey consisted of a 20min long boat from the bottom of the garden of Souchitra guest house (opposite our guest house) across the Mekong to Ban Muang, then a minivan for 90 mins down to Hat Xai Kun, followed by a 10min small longtail back across the Mekong to Muang Khong on Don Khong island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 166 &amp; 167 – Saturday 26th to Sunday 27th February – Champasak – Wat Phu Champasak</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/03/day-166-167-saturday-26th-to-sunday-27th-february-champasak-wat-phu-champasak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 10:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/04/03/day-166-167-saturday-26th-to-sunday-27th-february-champasak-wat-phu-champasak/</guid>
      <description>After a nice lie-in, the first in a while, a good banana pancake for brekkie from the local Indian, also a first in a while, and an excellent cup of coffee we jumped in a “remork-moto” to the new market (Talat Dao Heung) bus station. There have been many different designs of tuk-tuk in Lao and this was our first sat aside a motorbike in a 2 person carriage that looks like it might from a ferris wheel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 164 &amp; 165 – Thursday 24th to Friday 25th February – Green Discovery Tree Top Explorer 2 day trek</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/05/day-164-165-thursday-24th-to-friday-25th-february-green-discovery-tree-top-explorer-2-day-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 14:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/05/day-164-165-thursday-24th-to-friday-25th-february-green-discovery-tree-top-explorer-2-day-trek/</guid>
      <description>Don’t know where to begin with the last two days. Out of this world is one way to describe them.
Tree Top Explorer is a new venture run by Green Discovery that has only been running 2 months.
Our trek begins 90mins outside of Pakse at a village south of Paksong in the heart of the Bolaven Plateau famous for its coffee. We stop at a house with a woman roasting coffee beans in a wok over a low fire and where thousands of coffee beans are drying in the backyard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 163 – Wednesday 23rd February – Tha Khaek to Pakse</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/05/day-163-wednesday-23rd-february-tha-khaek-to-pakse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 14:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/05/day-163-wednesday-23rd-february-tha-khaek-to-pakse/</guid>
      <description>Got our backsides in order today and got out of bed and to the bus station in time for the 9am local bus to Pakse. This was the busiest bus we’ve been on so far in Laos. Only 1 mile after starting out there were more people than seats so the plastic stools once again came out and by the time we arrived in Pakse 5 hours later the aisle was full of people sitting on stools (or the floor and leaning on stools trying to sleep) with at least 4 people standing at the front.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 161 &amp; 162 – Monday 21st to Tuesday 22nd February – Savannakhet – Eco-guide Unit homestay &amp; trek</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-161-162-monday-21st-to-tuesday-22nd-february-savannakhet-eco-guide-unit-homestay-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 06:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-161-162-monday-21st-to-tuesday-22nd-february-savannakhet-eco-guide-unit-homestay-trek/</guid>
      <description>It’s now 16:30 on Tuesday and just got back from a 2 day spiritual trek around the local area with a night in a homestay at a local village.
It started at a salt factory about 18km from Savannakhet. The Japanese had drilled for oil and instead found salt water which is pumped out of the ground and either dried in the sun for 2 to 3 days or boiled in big vats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 160 – Sunday 20th February – Tha Khaek to Savannakhet</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-160-sunday-20th-february-tha-khaek-to-savannakhet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 06:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-160-sunday-20th-february-tha-khaek-to-savannakhet/</guid>
      <description>Our bus journey from Tha Khaek was quite an interesting one. They played an array of cheesy music videos. Some young kids prancing around. And one old guy. Well say in his late 50s, singing four or five different songs that all sounded the same and for each video he was wearing a shirt and tie and was either stood at the side of a main road with the limestone cliffs in the background or in a field dancing like your dad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 158 to 159 – Friday 18th to Saturday 19th February – Tha Khaek</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-158-to-159-friday-18th-to-saturday-19th-february-tha-khaek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 05:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-158-to-159-friday-18th-to-saturday-19th-february-tha-khaek/</guid>
      <description>Tha Khaek is a funny one. There’s not much here but every guesthouse was full on Friday evening. After trying 4 different guesthouses we ended up in the dodgy Khammouane Inter Guest House next door to the Karaoke, with a single bed masquerading as a double bed. I use the word bed in the loosest of terms as the mattress was rock hard and sunken in the middle. There were no curtains on the rails and the wooden shutters were covered by torn mossie nets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 157 – Thursday 17th February – Vientiane – Admin day</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-157-thursday-17th-february-vientiane-admin-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 05:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-157-thursday-17th-february-vientiane-admin-day/</guid>
      <description>Had a very constructive day doing admin type stuff.
Picked up our passports from the Immigration office and we are now permitted to stay in Laos until 10th March.
Arranged a way of leaving Vientiane (bus to Tha Khaek tomorrow). As lovely as it is 5 nights is enough when there is so much more of Laos to see. We have been staying at Mixay Paradise Guest House so long now that we were eligible for a free coffee and muffin this afternoon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 156 – Wednesday 16th February – Vientiane – Pha That Luang, COPE centre, bowling &amp; Matt gets a haircut</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-156-wednesday-16th-february-vientiane-pha-that-luang-cope-centre-bowling-matt-gets-a-haircut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 05:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-156-wednesday-16th-february-vientiane-pha-that-luang-cope-centre-bowling-matt-gets-a-haircut/</guid>
      <description>Hired bikes from the Youth Inn. Very Parisian with their little wicker baskets on the front.
Went back to the Immigration Office to renew our passports. It takes 24hours so we’re in Vientiane for a couple more days.
Most temples and museums are shut between 12:00 &amp;amp; 13:00 so we sat under the Patuxai (Arc de Triomphe) with a beer &amp;amp; a water to shade from the midday sun. Monday &amp;amp; Tuesday were overcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 154 to 155 – Monday 14th to Tuesday 15th February – Vientiane</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-154-to-155-monday-14th-to-tuesday-15th-february-vientiane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 05:51:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/03/04/day-154-to-155-monday-14th-to-tuesday-15th-february-vientiane/</guid>
      <description>Had a lovely Valentine’s Day in Vientiane. Moved hotels next door to Mixay Paradise Guest House so now we have a cleaner, more modern room with big windows and views over the temple and brekkie included (heart shaped fried-eggs, toast and curry). Although today’s wasn’t too bad as I had American style pancakes with crispy bacon which I thought I was putting maple syrup on but turned out it to be soya sauce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 153 – Sunday 13th February 2011 – Vientiane capital of Laos</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-153-sunday-13th-february-2011-vientiane-capital-of-laos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-153-sunday-13th-february-2011-vientiane-capital-of-laos/</guid>
      <description>Thought for the day
It’s 6pm on Sunday evening and I am sat at the Vista wifi cafe in Vientiane surrounded by laptops. Virtually every table is staring at one (me included) even whilst eating dinner there are people leaning across their plates typing away. They’re not sat alone either. (I currently am. Matt is off wandering for an hour as it’s our anniversary tomorrow so he’s doing some shopping I assume).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 152 – Saturday 12th February – Vang Vieng – more tubing the sensible way</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-152-saturday-12th-february-vang-vieng-more-tubing-the-sensible-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-152-saturday-12th-february-vang-vieng-more-tubing-the-sensible-way/</guid>
      <description>Happy birthday Dulcie!
Decided to go tubing again today and our mission was to go all the way down the river back to Vang Vieng before 6pm. We started out at 10:30 and met a couple from Holland called Edo and Annalies in the tuk-tuk there who had done trans-mongolian, china, thailand, cambodia, now laos and onto myanmar and thailand. We arranged to meet for a drink later so they could give us their Cambodia book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 148 to 151 – Tuesday 8th to Friday 11th February – Vang Vieng – Week 2 EEFA English teaching</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-148-to-151-tuesday-8th-to-friday-11th-february-vang-vieng-week-2-eefa-english-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-148-to-151-tuesday-8th-to-friday-11th-february-vang-vieng-week-2-eefa-english-teaching/</guid>
      <description>Happy 30th Birthday Lisa &amp;amp; Happy Birthday Leah!
Tuesday
Back to teaching yesterday and today was jam-packed. Had the same class at the primary school again. This time Mikael another volunteer came and helped me.
Tuesday evening I taught Level 1-1 again on my own this time. Which was fine for a while but soon became rowdy. I played a running game with them where they had to draw pictures on the board and write the word I was saying like Cat, Hat, Fan, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 147 – Monday 7th February – Vang Vieng – Karen’s 33rd birthday</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-147-monday-7th-february-vang-vieng-karens-33rd-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-147-monday-7th-february-vang-vieng-karens-33rd-birthday/</guid>
      <description>It’s my birthday and my nan’s. Happy Birthday Nan!!
Early brekkie at the most basic cafe you can imagine with a lovely little family running it. We’d been here a couple of times before as the views are fantastic. The little girl is so cute. She can hardly be 1 year old and likes teetering around in her mum’s high heels.Hired the same moped again for 5 days. I am becoming a pro now :) And headed off to the farm for the 9am meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 144 to 146 – Friday 4th to Sunday 6th February – Vang Vieng – Karen’s birthday weekend – caves &amp; tubing</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-144-to-146-friday-4th-to-sunday-6th-february-vang-vieng-karens-birthday-weekend-caves-tubing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-144-to-146-friday-4th-to-sunday-6th-february-vang-vieng-karens-birthday-weekend-caves-tubing/</guid>
      <description>Today changed our opinion of Vang Vieng. We saw a different side to it.
No teaching so we had the whole day to ourselves. After a good-lie in and a chilled out brekkie lounging on raised platforms overlooking the Nam Song river and the karsts beyond, we took the moped for a drive across the countryside. And I mean across it. There aren’t many roads the other side of the river and to get to many of the “sightseeing” places such as caves and viewpoints you need to go across farmland, dodging chickens and cows and rocks and streams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 140 to 143 – Monday 31st January to Thursday 4th February – Vang Vieng – Week 1 EEFA English Teaching through the Organic Farm</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-140-to-143-monday-31st-january-to-thursday-4th-february-vang-vieng-week-1-eefa-english-teaching-through-the-organic-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-140-to-143-monday-31st-january-to-thursday-4th-february-vang-vieng-week-1-eefa-english-teaching-through-the-organic-farm/</guid>
      <description>Before heading to Laos I contacted the EEFA Project. EEFA stands for Equal Education For All and is based at the Organic Farm 4km from Vang Vieng in Phoudindeng. I signed up for 2 weeks of volunteering as an English teacher. A chance to use the TEFL skills and to give something back.
Monday morning I was scared to death. I had no real experience of teaching or of working with kids whatsover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 138 to 139 – Saturday 29th to Sunday 30th January – Vang Vieng – initial impressions</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-138-to-139-saturday-29th-to-sunday-30th-january-vang-vieng-initial-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 11:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/20/day-138-to-139-saturday-29th-to-sunday-30th-january-vang-vieng-initial-impressions/</guid>
      <description>Vang Vieng is a 7.5 hour bus journey from LP. We were told we were buying a ticket for the 6 hour special VIP trip. They forgot to mention that when the 8am and 9am bus was already full, the 9:30am bus was in fact a less expensive VIP trip with no loo and dismal aircon that took longer but were happy to charge us the same price. If anyone else in Luang Prabang is going to Vang Vieng the ticket at the bus station costs only 90,000 kip for the 9:30 trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 133 to 137 cont… Luang Prabang – Phousi hill, Kop Noi, UXO Lao &amp; sunsets</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/18/day-133-to-137-cont-luang-prabang-phousi-hill-kop-noi-uxo-lao-sunsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 04:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/18/day-133-to-137-cont-luang-prabang-phousi-hill-kop-noi-uxo-lao-sunsets/</guid>
      <description>Whilst I spent my mornings at Big Brother Mouse, Matt concentrated on stolencamerafinder (check it out!). We almost fell into a normal routine. We’d both be up before 8am, ready to go get a breakfast baguette &amp;amp; a strong Lao coffee or Jasmine tea from the local Lao ladies. Matt would have chicken and I would go for Lao-style which is tofu, omelette and some brown hairy stuff.
Then we’d part ways and I’d go on my 10 min walk through the town or the morning market to Big Brother Mouse and Matt would go back to the guest house and get coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Anniversary Matt!</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/14/happy-anniversary-matt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 04:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/14/happy-anniversary-matt/</guid>
      <description>As well as being Valentine’s Day today it is 6 years today since our “non-date” in Wagamamas in Bristol when we hoped no-one we knew would pass the window and spot us just being 2 “friends” out for a meal on what just happened to be Valentine’s Day.
Since then I’ve had the most amazing years ever. And I’m so glad that Matt was up for the same mad plan of giving up everything and going travelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 133 to 137 – Monday 24th to Friday 28th January – Luang Prabang – volunteering at Big Brother Mouse</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-133-to-137-monday-24th-to-friday-28th-january-luang-prabang-volunteering-at-big-brother-mouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 12:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-133-to-137-monday-24th-to-friday-28th-january-luang-prabang-volunteering-at-big-brother-mouse/</guid>
      <description>After 7 days in Luang Prabang we are still not ready to leave. This has to be one of our favourite places of the trip for easy living. It is a beautiful place and the people are so friendly.
I have been volunteering at Big Brother Mouse, a local charity which creates books for kids in Lao and English. They encourage tourists to buy books from their shop or from the market to give to kids who live in villages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 132 – Sunday 23rd January – Luang Prabang</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-132-sunday-23rd-january-luang-prabang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 10:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-132-sunday-23rd-january-luang-prabang/</guid>
      <description>Moved guest house again as although the bed was extra comfy the plumbing had a dodgy odour and there seemed to be a loud woman banging on the doors at all hours. We are far too old for such nonsense. And we were glad to check out as the guy on the desk tried to charge us $15 instead of the 100,000 kip we were quoted. Very rude. Later happened to come across it on Tripadvisor and it was something like #76 our of #98 B&amp;amp;Bs in Luang Prabang and most of the reviews were terrible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 131 – Saturday 22nd January – Pak Beng to Luang Prabang (day 2 of the slow boat down the Mekong river)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-131-saturday-22nd-january-pak-beng-to-luang-prabang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 10:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-131-saturday-22nd-january-pak-beng-to-luang-prabang/</guid>
      <description>Another earlyish start. After yesterday’s overflowing boat we wanted to make sure we got a seat. We boarded the boat at 8:10 for a 9:00 departure to find it was a different boat from yesterday. This time there were about 20 car seats and the rest were stiff wooden benches about 8cm deep.
At least we had a seat though. And there were cushions too covered in teddy bear material and many people didn’t get a seat so can’t complain (much).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 130 – Friday 21st January – Huay Xai to Pak Beng (day 1 of the slow boat down the Mekong River)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-130-friday-21st-january-huay-xai-to-pak-beng-day-1-of-the-slow-boat-down-the-mekong-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 09:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-130-friday-21st-january-huay-xai-to-pak-beng-day-1-of-the-slow-boat-down-the-mekong-river/</guid>
      <description>Not sure what to write about today. It gave us doubts about travelling. Made us feel old. Well me anyway. And like we’d missed the boat (excuse the pun). Yep we have spent all day on a boat full of young twenty-something travellers.
Got up early so we could have breakfast at 8am in time for the boat pickup at 8.30. Pickup then wasn’t til 9.10. Fine OK no problem. Dropped off at the harbourside with our ticket &amp;amp; boat no.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 129 – Thursday 20th January – Thailand to Laos</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-129-thursday-20th-january-thailand-to-laos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 09:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-129-thursday-20th-january-thailand-to-laos/</guid>
      <description>After exactly 1 month in Thailand we are now in Laos.
It was pretty simple. We jumped on a rickety old bus from Chiang Rai, our bags piled high at the back of the bus with everyone else’s luggage and our knees up under our chins (well Matt’s anyway) and 2.5 hours later we were dropped off at a tuk-tuk stand in Chiang Khong on the border with Laos. 5 min tuk-tuk ride and we were at the Mekong River and border crossing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 128 – Wednesday 19th January – Chiang Rai to Myanmar &amp; back</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-128-wednesday-19th-january-chiang-rai-to-myanmar-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 08:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/13/day-128-wednesday-19th-january-chiang-rai-to-myanmar-back/</guid>
      <description>We went to Myanmar (Burma) today for 2 reasons.
One: we wanted to visit Myanmar (our 6th country so far if you include Nepal :) )
Two: our Thai visa ran out today so we needed to leave the country or pay a fine
It was a surreal and yet dull experience. And far too easy.
10:00 Bus Chiang Rai to Mae Sai (Thai border town)
11:30 Sorng Thaew from Mae Sai bus station to the border</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 126 &amp; 127 – Monday 17th to Tuesday 18th January – Chiang Rai</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/12/day-126-127-monday-17th-to-tuesday-18th-january-chiang-rai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 16:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/12/day-126-127-monday-17th-to-tuesday-18th-january-chiang-rai/</guid>
      <description>The longtail trip down the Mae Nam Kok river (a tributary of the Mae Kong (Mekong) river) was a lovely way of getting to Chiang Rai from the sleepy town of Thaton. It took 3.5 hours including a 20min loo/coffee stop with the most expensive coffee ever. 50THB for half a cup of “Americano”. If we’d gone for Nescafe we would have saved ourselves 30THB per cup! At the pitstop there was also a guy holding a huge great long python saying “photo, photo”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 125 – Sunday 16th January – Thaton</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/08/day-125-sunday-16th-january-thaton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 15:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/02/08/day-125-sunday-16th-january-thaton/</guid>
      <description>Dragged Matt out of bed early so we could make it to the bus station for the 9am bus to Thaton. For some reason everyone we met knew we were heading to Thaton – the tuk tuk driver, the guys at the bus station. Perhaps it’s the only bus that “farang” (foreigners) get from the Chang Pheuak bus station in Chiang Rai.
This was our first ordinary bus journey. A bus with 2 seats one side, 3 seats the other side (similar to before) but with fans and windows that open instead of aircon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 122 to 124 – Thursday 13th to Saturday 15th January – Chiang Mai (phase 2 – Matt is old)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/28/day-122-to-124-thursday-13th-to-saturday-15th-january-chiang-mai-phase-2-matt-is-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 11:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/28/day-122-to-124-thursday-13th-to-saturday-15th-january-chiang-mai-phase-2-matt-is-old/</guid>
      <description>Congratulations to Helen &amp;amp; Martyn on the birth of their daughter Alys Kate on 13th.
4 months travelling. It feels like we have done so much but nothing at the same time and we’re already a third of the way through. :(
13th – Moved down-market today to MD House in the old city. Partly because we couldn’t justify paying for Butterfly anymore and partly because we wanted to see a bit more of Chiang Mai instead of lazing around by the pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 120 &amp; 121 – Tuesday 11th to Wednesday 12th January – Chiang Mai (phase 1 – Matt’s 30th Birthday)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/20/day-120-121-tuesday-11th-to-wednesday-12th-january-chiang-mai-phase-1-matts-30th-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 04:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/20/day-120-121-tuesday-11th-to-wednesday-12th-january-chiang-mai-phase-1-matts-30th-birthday/</guid>
      <description>On Christmas Day in Ko Lanta I said Does life get any better than this? The answer is Oh yes! If you stay in the most amazing resort called Butterfly in Chiang Mai.
This was Matt’s main birthday pressie. I was a little concerned because the resort was on the outskirts of Chiang Mai and I was worried we’d be too far away from bars and restaurants for celebrating.
I needn’t have worried.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 118 &amp; 119 – Sunday 9th to Monday 10th January – Sukhothai</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/18/day-118-119-sunday-9th-to-monday-10th-january-sukhothai/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 13:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/18/day-118-119-sunday-9th-to-monday-10th-january-sukhothai/</guid>
      <description>Arrived in Sukhothai after a 5.5 hour bus journey. This time 1st class so normal sized seats but included a free lunch stop at a service station. You could choose what you wanted from an array of dishes and Matt &amp;amp; I both chose at random as we had no idea what anything was. The server said “Spicy” in a way that we shouldn’t want it but yes of course we want it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 117 – Saturday 8th January – Ayutthaya</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/18/day-117-saturday-8th-january-ayutthaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 13:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/18/day-117-saturday-8th-january-ayutthaya/</guid>
      <description>From now on Matt doesn’t know where we’re going or staying. It’s kind of a birthday pressie for him. No stress of having to worry about route or accommodation. So I’ve booked the next few days already.
Our first train experience in Thailand from Bangkok to Ayutthaya was pleasant. Although not sleeper trains it reminded us of India with the shutters and open windows and people walking by with baskets of sandwiches, drinks and dried fish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 116 – Friday 7th January – Bangkok (Shopping)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/18/day-116-friday-7th-january-bangkok-shopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 13:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/18/day-116-friday-7th-january-bangkok-shopping/</guid>
      <description>Got a taxi to the Siam Square area of Bangkok to go shopping! The place was filled with giant malls, street sellers and small narrow back alleys filled with cute little clothes shops. A shopper’s heaven. I could have spent a fortune.
Spent an extremely long time in MBK mall. The food mall was enormous. You buy coupons from the cashier and then go to one of the 40 food places to get your food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 115 – Thursday 6th January – Bangkok (Temples)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/18/day-115-thursday-6th-january-bangkok-temples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 13:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/18/day-115-thursday-6th-january-bangkok-temples/</guid>
      <description>Our overnight VIP bus from Krabi to Bangkok had 3 seats per row with lots of room, blankets, free coffee &amp;amp; bun, water and free dinner. Not that we realised all of this until we got on the bus. We’d stuffed ourselves beforehand so a stop with free buffet was a surprise.
Another surprise came at 3am when the onboard hostess tapped me on the head twice to wake me and give me a refreshing towel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 112 to 114 – Monday 3rd to Wednesday 5th January – Krabi</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-112-to-114-monday-3rd-to-wednesday-5th-january-krabi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 13:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-112-to-114-monday-3rd-to-wednesday-5th-january-krabi/</guid>
      <description>Beach time is over. Back to the proper mainland and the rest of Thailand.
Our last bit of Railay sightseeing was the Diamond Cave. We’d walked past it every time we’d been anywhere away from Railay Cabana.
On the way to the cave Matt informed me what had been in his towel…a scorpion. Which had crawled on him. Only when he’d knocked it onto the ground had he seen what it was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 111 – Sunday 2nd January – Railay</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-111-sunday-2nd-january-railay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 13:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-111-sunday-2nd-january-railay/</guid>
      <description>Just about recovered from New Year shenanigans now and we ventured to the 4th and final beach in the Railay area. It is reachable by longtail from West beach, by walking from West beach (we believe) or by walking from Railay East. The pathway from East is right outside Railay Cabana so it was an easy choice to make. Not so easy walk though although it was lovely to walk through the jungle and see more amazing butterflies, we saw the “Tsunami village” where there were a few shells of buildings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 110 – Saturday 1st January 2011 – Railay</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-110-saturday-1st-january-2011-railay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 13:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-110-saturday-1st-january-2011-railay/</guid>
      <description>Stayed in bed almost all day and lived on pringles, oreos and coke.
Now we know why drinking is bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 109 – Friday 31st December – Railay NEW YEAR’s EVE</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-109-friday-31st-december-railay-new-years-eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 13:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-109-friday-31st-december-railay-new-years-eve/</guid>
      <description>Bungalows next door are booked up so we’ve resigned ourselves to staying at Railay Cabana for 2 more nights. I am now prepared for cockroaches. And the small green frog in the bathroom was more cute than scary. Although Matt reminded me today to shake towels and clothing before using them in case you come across an unwanted inhabitant. He didn’t tell me what he found in his towel after a shower and I don’t want to know…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 108 – Thursday 30th December – Railay</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-108-thursday-30th-december-railay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 12:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/13/day-108-thursday-30th-december-railay/</guid>
      <description>Rock-climbing in Railay is (apologies for americanism here but it needs to be used) awesome. Would definitely recommend it to anyone. I’ve never really climbed outdoors before and it is is completely different to indoors. I managed to do 4.5 climbs and Matt did 6. The weather couldn’t have been better. It was dry but overcast whereas later it rained and since then it’s been sweltering.
 Karen
 Matt Matt</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 107 – Wednesday 29th December – Railay, Thailand</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/10/day-107-wednesday-29th-december-railay-thailand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 03:22:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/10/day-107-wednesday-29th-december-railay-thailand/</guid>
      <description>Checked out of bland Harmony House at 10:35 and legged it to the main port of Koh Phi Phi nabbing a ticket on the way to catch the 11am ferry to Krabi and “free transfer” to Ao Nang. Intention was to check out Ao Nang and then go onto Railay. Settled down on a ledge at the back of the ferry alfresco and watched beautiful angelfish darting around the coral attached to the jetty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 105 to 106 – Monday 27th to Tuesday 28th December – Ko Phi Phi</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/09/d-ay-105-to-106-monday-27th-to-tuesday-28th-december-ko-phi-phi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 03:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/09/d-ay-105-to-106-monday-27th-to-tuesday-28th-december-ko-phi-phi/</guid>
      <description>Picked up by a pick up truck to go to Koh Lanta ferry &amp;amp; 90mins later land at Koh Phi Phi. Doesn’t seem to be much accommodation left so we end up at Harmony House the cheapest the touts could find for us. It doesn’t start off well. One girl is checking out because of noise and smells. Another 2 girls want out as guys have been trying to bash their doors down in the night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 101 to 104 – Thursday 23rd to Sunday 26th December – Ko Lanta</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/09/day-101-to-104-thursday-23rd-to-sunday-26th-december-ko-lanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 03:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/09/day-101-to-104-thursday-23rd-to-sunday-26th-december-ko-lanta/</guid>
      <description>Nice early pickup at 7.15am to get the 8.30am ferry to Ko Phi Phi. The weather was gorgeous and the view of the limestone karsts of Phi Phi appearing in the distance was amazing. Hopped off and hopped onto another ferry to Ko Lanta where a woman was selling ice-creams. Genius idea.
Arrived in Ko Lanta and met off the boat by 2 guys from Fevrier resort who bundled us, another couple and our bags into the back of a pickup truck for the 20min journey to Klong Nin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 100 – Wednesday 22nd December – Phuket, Thailand</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/04/day-100-wednesday-22nd-december-phuket-thailand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 15:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/04/day-100-wednesday-22nd-december-phuket-thailand/</guid>
      <description>100 days into our adventure and today wasn’t particularly eventful.
In Hat Karon, Phuket and there are “girlie” bars everywhere and lots of middle-aged european men with pretty young Thai ladies on their arm. Or two or three guys sat at a table with one girl.
The beach is lovely, although mostly covered in sunloungers, we found a spot to lay a towel and sunbathed for half an hour before we could bear the heat no longer and went for a wander around the streets full of souvenier shops, clothes shops and restaurants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 99 – Tuesday 21st December – Pangkor to KL to Phuket</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/04/day-99-tuesday-21st-december-pangkor-to-kl-to-phuket/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 15:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/04/day-99-tuesday-21st-december-pangkor-to-kl-to-phuket/</guid>
      <description>Another mental journey planned by us. Instead of going overland up to Krabi we decided to fly to Phuket from Kuala Lumpur. So we could get the 30-day visa instead of the 15-day visa. (For some reason there is a difference in Thailand depending on whether you enter overland or via an airport???)
Our journey:
7.45am Pink minibus taxi from Telak Nipah to Pangkor Town
8.30am Ferry from Pangkor Town to Lumut</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 96 to 98 – Saturday 18th to Monday 20th December – Pulau Pangkor</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/04/day-96-to-98-saturday-18th-to-monday-20th-december-pulau-pangkor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 15:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/04/day-96-to-98-saturday-18th-to-monday-20th-december-pulau-pangkor/</guid>
      <description>5 hour bus journey from KL to Lumut further up the coast, caught the last ferry to Pulau Pangkor and arrived at a car park full of baby pink ford rascal minibuses. The taxi dropped us off in Telak Nipah, the most budget bit of the island and we went to our selected B&amp;amp;B to ask for room. Sorry full. Next one. Sorry full. Next one…and so on until we’d exhausted every guest house &amp;amp; hotel in Telak Nipah.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 95 – Friday 17th December – Kuala Lumpur</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-95-friday-17th-december-kuala-lumpur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 13:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-95-friday-17th-december-kuala-lumpur/</guid>
      <description>Matt got up at dawn to go find the perfect view of the Petronas towers and came back 3 hours later with his sunrise timelapse from the KLCC park and was knackered so snoozed whilst I trawled the internet for ideas on what to do for Christmas. So many places to decide on. Found cheap flights to Bali but does it make sense to go that way or should we head overland through Malaysia and up to Thailand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 94 – Thursday 16th December – Melaka to Kuala Lumpur</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-94-thursday-16th-december-melaka-to-kuala-lumpur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 12:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-94-thursday-16th-december-melaka-to-kuala-lumpur/</guid>
      <description>More dim sum yum. Extra this time. Felt like pigs but the food here is lush.
Sam from Jalan Jalan was brilliant in advising us to walk to the bottom of Chinatown instead of the top to catch the local bus to the bus station. I’d read that it could take an hour from the square but it took less than 10 mins from the other end. Fab. We always seem to travel with our backpacks when the sun is hottest and today was particularly muggy and humid inbetween the rain showers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 92 &amp; 93 – Tuesday 14th to Wednesday 15th December – Melaka, Malaysia</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-92-93-tuesday-14th-to-wednesday-15th-december-melaka-malaysia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 12:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-92-93-tuesday-14th-to-wednesday-15th-december-melaka-malaysia/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday 14th December and we have been travelling for exactly 3 months and we’re now in Malaysia. Can’t believe how fast the time is going.
Took a lovely luxury bus from Singapore to Melaka. The border crossings were simple. Off the bus at one side of the bridge to exit Singapore and get our passport stamped. Then off the bus again the other side of the bridge to get our entry to Malaysia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 91 – Monday 13th December – Singapore</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-91-monday-13th-december-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 12:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-91-monday-13th-december-singapore/</guid>
      <description>Met up with Dulcie’s sister Esme, her husband Gus &amp;amp; 3-month baby Cleo for lunch as they are currently living in Singapore. Had lunch at a very lush Indonesian restaurant where we fell in love with Beef Penang and I fell for lychee juice made which comes with fresh lychees in the glass. Not sure Matt fell in love with his bright pink strawberry fizzy shake but he had to try it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 90 – Sunday 12th December – Singapore</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-90-sunday-12th-december-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 12:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-90-sunday-12th-december-singapore/</guid>
      <description>Bloomin’ ‘eck today was hot. Another partial downside is the temperature. Being so close to the equator it is very hot all day long. Even at midnight it is still very warm. So air-conditioning is everywhere, even outside cooling the streets in some places. A big waste of energy and very environmentally unfriendly.
Visited Chinatown. The cleanest Chinatown I’ve ever been to. Very delicious food (dumpling soup and char siew wonton noodles) and cheapish beer compared to the rest of Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 89 – Saturday 11th December – Singapore</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-89-saturday-11th-december-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 12:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-89-saturday-11th-december-singapore/</guid>
      <description>2 weeks til Xmas!
Singapore is completely different to India. It’s kind of been a bit of a “culture-shock” for us and we’re having to adapt to another way of living again.
It is very American-like with huge roads, sky-scrapers and 7-11s everywhere. And it is so very clean (even the money) and organised. Almost futuristic. People in cars stop for you at zebra crossings. It has a great metro system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 88 – Friday 10th December – Mumbai to Singapore</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-88-friday-10th-december-mumbai-to-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 12:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-88-friday-10th-december-mumbai-to-singapore/</guid>
      <description>Early start today as we’re off on our 2nd leg to Singapore!
Up at 5.30, had a lovely cold shower and no breakfast. Specifically asked the guys in reception last night about breakfast before 6am and they said no problem. We’d also checked when hot water was available – 5am til 12pm (stupid – why have it only switched on in the morning? Don’t people shower in the evenings?) Matt went to enquire about the water &amp;amp; breakfast and had to practically stand on the guy in reception to wake him up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 87 – Thursday 9th December – Mumbai</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-87-thursday-9th-december-mumbai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 12:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-87-thursday-9th-december-mumbai/</guid>
      <description>A taxi took us to our over-priced hotel Cowie’s in Walton Street. We don’t know what that place is trying to be but it’s not getting enough right. And everyone who works there expects tips for nothing. We had 4 of us in a tiny lift plus our backpacks because 2 guys felt the need to help us to our room! Can’t complain about the location though. It’s about 10mins from Gateway of India and Taj Hotel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 85 &amp; 86 – Tuesday 7th &amp; Wednesday 8th December – Goa</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-85-86-tuesday-7th-wednesday-8th-december-goa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 11:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-85-86-tuesday-7th-wednesday-8th-december-goa/</guid>
      <description>I can’t be bothered to go into the fiasco at Margao Residency. All-in-all we got there at 8am and didn’t get our room until 10am so were pretty pissed off knackered peeps by then. 2hrs probably doesn’t sound that bad but try 2hrs when you have been in a sleeper bus for 10hrs followed by a cafe for 3hours and you’re feeling icky.
Finally found that beaches do exist in Goa :) Got the sardine bus to Benaulim town, walked the 15 mins to the beach, found a beach bar called Rogers and drank beer for 2 hours looking at the sand &amp;amp; sea and the package-holiday beach whales lying on their sunloungers snapping their fingers at waiters to bring them more beers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Night 84/Morning 85 – Hampi to Goa</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/night-84morning-85-hampi-to-goa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 11:56:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/night-84morning-85-hampi-to-goa/</guid>
      <description>…30 mins after leaving Hospet, we stopped at a service station. All traipsed off to the loo shack where of course only 1 out of the 3 loos was unlocked. I was next in the queue and there was a powercut. Everywhere went pitch black. I didn’t quite think I could bring myself to pee in the dark when you can’t see where you’re putting your feet so trotted back too get the torch (little did I know…see later that night).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 83 &amp; 84 – Sunday 5th &amp; Monday 6th December – Hampi</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-83-84-sunday-5th-monday-6th-december-hampi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 11:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-83-84-sunday-5th-monday-6th-december-hampi/</guid>
      <description>Left Goa at 7.30am and arrived Hospet at 3ish. Somehow it is easy for us now to sit on a train for over 7hrs.
We were in Sleeper class for the first time and we prefer it to 3A/C. Can’t say what it would be like overnight but during the day it was nice to be able to see the outside world passing by. There are windows and shutters but both can be opened as you like to let in air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 82 – Saturday 4th December – Margao, Goa</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-82-saturday-4th-december-margao-goa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 11:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-82-saturday-4th-december-margao-goa/</guid>
      <description>Finally escaped the hospital at 11:00, Matt armed with prescription for more drugs we headed for trusted Margao Residency, our bland business Goa hotel.
Matt didn’t know what to do. Fresh air. No nurses. No stuff being pumped into his arm. Weird concept. He is much better which is good as we don’t want to go back to hospital any time soon – even if it was cheaper than the hotel and had larger rooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 81 – Friday 3rd December – Margao</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-81-friday-3rd-december-margao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 11:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/03/day-81-friday-3rd-december-margao/</guid>
      <description>Still in hospital but this is definitely the last night and we’re out of here tomorrow morning. Free! Matt is feeling much better &amp;amp; is ecstatic at the thought of leaving. He’s had enough of goop being pumped into his arm and lying down for hours watching TV.
Another trip to the market for veggies and heard Mary’s Boy Child blasting out of someone’s ghetto blaster. Hearing xmas carols makes me a little homesick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year!</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/02/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 13:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2011/01/02/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>Happy 2011 everyone. Hope you all had a lovely christmas and NYE. We spent all day recovering yesterday after one too many cocktails.
Will update more blog when we get back to wifi land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Christmas!</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/25/happy-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 07:57:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/25/happy-christmas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 79 &amp; 80 – Wednesday 1st to Thursday 2nd December – Margao, Goa</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-79-to-80-wednesday-1st-to-thursday-2nd-december-margao-goa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 06:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-79-to-80-wednesday-1st-to-thursday-2nd-december-margao-goa/</guid>
      <description>We have spent most of December so far in hospital. Matt completely lost his appetite and by the time we arrived in Goa he was feeling sick and everything else all over again. We checked into Margao Residency (with hot water!) and both slept for a few hours (neither of us had much sleep on the train). By 5pm he was in such a state I made him see a doctor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 78 – Tuesday 30th November – Fort Kochin</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-78-tuesday-30th-november-fort-kochin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 06:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-78-tuesday-30th-november-fort-kochin/</guid>
      <description>Today was a weird one. Stayed in Fort Kochin most of the day as our train to Goa wasn’t until 22:30. Braved the post office again to send a couple of parcels. Managed to get it all sewn up neatly and posted in less than 2hrs so not too bad.
Spent a lot of time chilling in Teapot. I am hooked on black tea and Jasmine tea now. Never thought we’d be drinking tea without milk but it tastes good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 77 – Monday 29th November – Fort Kochin &amp; Vypeen Island</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-77-monday-29th-november-fort-kochin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 06:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-77-monday-29th-november-fort-kochin/</guid>
      <description>Finally made it to Cherai Beach on Vypeen Island. We’d meant to go last time we were in Kochi but our written-off Sunday put paid to that. Matt was feeling much better too.
The plan was almost scuppered whilst on the way to the ferry. I was feeling a bit queasy so we sat down in the park for a couple of minutes. 2 seconds later a bloke came up to us to try to sell us an eel in a carrier bag – head and tail just poking out the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 76 – Sunday 28th November – Fort Cochin</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-76-sunday-28th-november-fort-cochin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 05:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-76-sunday-28th-november-fort-cochin/</guid>
      <description>We have left Alleppey, hooray! Matt is on the mend although not 100% so treated ourselves to a taxi from Alleppey to Fort Cochin. A bit extravagant but more predictable than the train or bus when you’re not feeling too well and we just wanted to move on from here as soon as possible. The taxi driver was very sweet. Mentioning Manchester United and David Beckham but not understanding us when we asked “Do you watch a lot of English football?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 75 – Saturday 27th November – Alleppey</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-75-saturday-27th-november-alleppey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 05:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-75-saturday-27th-november-alleppey/</guid>
      <description>Still in Alleppey. Matt is over the flu symptoms but has Delhi belly all over again. You’re meant to get it in the first 2 weeks of being in India not the last 2 weeks as well.
So decided it was best to stay put for another day as he can’t travel that far and get some antibiotics. We think we have some. Had to check it on wikipedia though ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 74 – Friday 26th November – Alleppey</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-74-friday-26th-november-alleppey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 05:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-74-friday-26th-november-alleppey/</guid>
      <description>12:00 We are still in Alleppey. The plan was to leave this morning and go 10km away to stay in the Green Palm Homes on the backwaters to experience life there for real. Unfortunately Matt is too unwell. He was fine last night after dinner but hardly slept and now has flu-like symptoms. So we are having a chill-out day in Alleppey and will decide what to do next when he is feeling a little better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 73 – Thursday 25th November – Alleppey</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-73-thursday-25th-november-alleppey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 05:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/12/22/day-73-thursday-25th-november-alleppey/</guid>
      <description>Backwater trip today. Before we’d even had breakfast we had our plans sorted. Volker Schmidt, a guy staying at Palmy Residency, asked us if we’d like to join him on a motor boat he’d hired as it was too big for one person. It made sense as we were going to look into doing a boat trip anyway. We have met lots of people with interesting jobs and Volker’s sounded pretty impressive – director &amp;amp; writer (previously actor) in Berlin and Vienna.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 72 – Wednesday 24th November – Alleppey</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/26/day-72-wednesday-24th-november-alleppey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 15:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/26/day-72-wednesday-24th-november-alleppey/</guid>
      <description>In Alleppey, the backwaters of Kerala, now after a very short train journey by Indian standards of 1hr 45mins at a ridiculously early time of 6:30.
Once again couldn’t sleep as I never can when we have to be up early to catch a plane or train. Matt on the other hand was almost out cold after drifting off whilst reading and smacking himself squarely on the nose with the e-reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 70 to 71 – Monday 22nd to Tuesday 23rd November – Varkala, Kerala</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/26/day-70-to-71-monday-22nd-to-tuesday-23rd-november-varkala-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 15:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/26/day-70-to-71-monday-22nd-to-tuesday-23rd-november-varkala-kerala/</guid>
      <description>Guess who we bumped onto last night? Isla &amp;amp; Neil. It was inevitable as we’ve been in Varkala over a week now. We’re not very good at this “travelling” lark are we. (We blame the railway system!) They’d been here since Sunday and lucky for them had avoided us for 2 days. We have arranged to meet up with them later for dinner. Our last night in Varkala before we head to Alleppey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 66 to 69 – Thursday 18th to Sunday 21st November – Varkala, Kerala</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/26/days-66-to-69-thursday-18th-to-sunday-21st-november-varkala-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 15:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/26/days-66-to-69-thursday-18th-to-sunday-21st-november-varkala-kerala/</guid>
      <description>It’s 21st November – Happy Birthday Ali!
Sat on our balcony at Mummy Bamboo House listening to the rain fall steadily through the palm trees onto the dirt tracks below and forming murky orange rivers. The sheets a local lady just hung up on lines between the trees are being thoroughly rinsed again. The taxi Rani’s husband drives is keeping dry under the makeshift tarpaulin garage. The monsoon season is well and truly back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 64 to 65 – Tuesday 16th to Wednesday 17th November – Varkala, Kerala</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/26/days-64-to-65-tuesday-16th-to-wednesday-17th-november-varkala-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 15:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/26/days-64-to-65-tuesday-16th-to-wednesday-17th-november-varkala-kerala/</guid>
      <description>Before I forget mum has received the parcel from Darjeeling and it’s in one piece! She thought it looked like drugs as it’s all wrapped in white muslin. It only took 3 weeks so that’s pretty good. I think it has beaten most of the postcards which seem to have been lost in the post.
 Tuesday morning joined the hardened commuters on the 5:50 train from Kochi and by 10:00 we were at Mummy Bamboo House in Varkala about a minute’s walk from the North Cliff edge overlooking the Indian Ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 61 to 63 – Saturday 13th to Monday 15th November – Fort Cochin, Kerala</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/23/days-61-to-63-saturday-13th-to-monday-15th-november-fort-cochin-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 18:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/23/days-61-to-63-saturday-13th-to-monday-15th-november-fort-cochin-kerala/</guid>
      <description>Saturday morning legged it from Seashore Residency and ended up in Elite Hotel on the main high street which is much much nicer. They had FOUR towels laid out on the bed without us even asking. And plenty of natural light. And no psycho bloke at the desk.
Wandered to Mantancherry on the other side of the island to Fort Cochin where I could have spent an absolute fortune. So many shops selling gorgeous jewellery, pashminas, cushion covers, ornaments you don’t need etc etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 60 – Friday 12th November – Kochi to Fort Cochin, Kerala</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/23/day-60-friday-12th-november-kochi-to-fort-cochin-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 18:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/23/day-60-friday-12th-november-kochi-to-fort-cochin-kerala/</guid>
      <description>Left Chennai at 10:45pm and arrived in Kochi at 11:30am Friday. The atmosphere here is completely different. The station was calm. Not too many people. And we found a Pizza Hut. Very sad but after our experiences of pizza in Havelock we needed it. Went to the Women Changing India photography exhibition in Kochi which Matt had spotted in a photography magazine. It was interesting to see how things are changing here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 59 – Thursday 11th November – Port Blair to Chennai to Kochi</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/18/day-59-thursday-11th-november-port-blair-to-chennai-to-kochi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 13:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/18/day-59-thursday-11th-november-port-blair-to-chennai-to-kochi/</guid>
      <description>Flight from Port Blair to Chennai was faultless. Kingfisher airlines were excellent. The flight was on time. The bus at Chennai from the plane to the terminal had armchairs &amp;amp; sofas to sit on. I am not kidding. Here I am trying to take a photo of both of us sat in one of the armchairs quickly before anyone sees me and arrests me for breaching airport security. This was embarrassingly the best one out of four attempts!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 56 to 58 – Monday 8th to Wednesday 10th November – Havelock Island &amp; Port Blair</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/18/days-56-to-58-monday-8th-to-wednesday-10th-november-havelock-island-port-blair/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 13:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/18/days-56-to-58-monday-8th-to-wednesday-10th-november-havelock-island-port-blair/</guid>
      <description>Sun is shining yay!
Spent most of Monday on our lovely little bit of secluded beach. Matt in the hammock hiding from the sun and me in as much sun as poss. Had bar-b-q fish again for dinner at Pellicon. This time we had the biggest chunk of tuna fillet I’ve ever seen and a delicious Silverfish marinated in tandoori sauce. Delish.
Tuesday we decided to get up for sunrise. Alarm set for 5am, we dragged ourselves out at 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 55 – Sunday 7th November – Havelock Island</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/18/day-55-sunday-7th-november-havelock-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 11:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/18/day-55-sunday-7th-november-havelock-island/</guid>
      <description>Happy 1st Anniversary to John &amp;amp; Kelly Wass! Can’t believe it’s been a whole year since your wedding. Time has flown. Miss you guys lots!
Our last day of diving today. It rained all night long heaviest we’d heard and was still raining at 6am when the alarm went off. But by the time we boarded Hammerhead the blue sky was winning and Matt has his first sunburn of the Andaman Islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 54 – Saturday 6th November – Havelock Island</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/18/day-54-saturday-6th-november-havelock-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 11:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/18/day-54-saturday-6th-november-havelock-island/</guid>
      <description>8am I woke up looked out the window saw blue sky and was like a small child on Christmas morning jumping around over-excitedly. Sunbathing here we come!
I rushed over to order to brekkie whilst Matt dragged himself sleepily out of bed and into the shower. Just as he came out of the hut the black clouds swallowed up the blue and the rains descended.
And it’s rained and rained and rained and rained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 53 – Friday 5th November – Havelock Island</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/day-53-friday-5th-november-havelock-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 16:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/day-53-friday-5th-november-havelock-island/</guid>
      <description>Happy Anniversary to Steve &amp;amp; Anne-Marie!
It’s bonfire night in the UK and you’d be forgiven for thinking they have the same tradition over here as kids are running round with sparklers and setting off fireworks and the loudest firecrackers I’ve ever heard giving this old woman many mini heart attacks. It’s the Diwali festival of lights today. Such a shame it’s hardly stopped raining. We have been in the hut most of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 45 to 52 – Thursday 28th October to Thursday 4th November – Andaman Islands</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/days-45-to-52-thursday-28th-october-to-thursday-4th-november-andaman-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 15:58:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/days-45-to-52-thursday-28th-october-to-thursday-4th-november-andaman-islands/</guid>
      <description>For the past week we have been in the Indian Ocean between the Bay of Bengal and the Andaman Sea on the tropical Havelock Island.
We landed in Port Blair on South Andaman Thursday afternoon and jumped in a taxi 15 mins before the last ferry was due to leave for Havelock. We were under no illusion that we’d get that ferry when we landed. But the information desk woman at the airport plus the taxi driver assured us we could make it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 44 – Wednesday 27th October – Kolkata</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/day-44-wednesday-27th-october-kolkata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 20:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/day-44-wednesday-27th-october-kolkata/</guid>
      <description>Kolkata (previously known as Calcutta although may still be known as Calcutta as many people still say they’re from Bombay even though its now Mumbai – must check this out) was a pleasant surprise for a large city.
We arrived late Tuesday night as our train took 2hrs longer than it needed to. Somehow Uli, the German trainee architect who is studying in Vienna, had wangled us a lift to our hotel with a lovely Kolkatan couple whose driver met them at the station in their new Jeep wagon thing that had room for a family of 10 and still had the bubble wrap on the spare wheel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 42 – Monday 25th October – Darjeeling</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/day-42-monday-25th-october-darjeeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 20:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/day-42-monday-25th-october-darjeeling/</guid>
      <description>Last day in Darjeeling and weather today is lovely. Khangchendzonga is clearly visible on above the skyline. It’s beautiful.
We stopped at our regular egg roll lady and acquired two on the way to Observatory Hill North East of centre to sit and admire the view of the mountain. Not quite as impressive a view as the one from Sandakphu but still not bad.
Stopped for tea tasting where the guy let us smell about 20 different samples of tea which he warmed in his palms first to release the aroma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 37 to 41 – Wednesday 20th to Sunday 24th October (Singalila Ridge Trek)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/days-37-to-41-wednesday-20th-to-sunday-24th-october-singalila-ridge-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 20:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/11/15/days-37-to-41-wednesday-20th-to-sunday-24th-october-singalila-ridge-trek/</guid>
      <description>I thought I would try and update the blog as haven’t written for over a week. What better time to do it than whilst Matt has his first shave in 6 weeks. I could be writing a novel here :)
Short version:
The trek was amazing. There were bad points, there always are with us two. But the result at the end was phenomenal. The views at sunrise across the Himalaya mountain range spectacular, breathtaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 36 – Tuesday 19th October – Darjeeling</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/19/day-36-tuesday-19th-october-darjeeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 16:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/19/day-36-tuesday-19th-october-darjeeling/</guid>
      <description>The sun came out today. Hooray! At 3pm after umming and ahhing and umming some more in our worse than normal indecisive manner, we finally made a decision to go on the trek. At 3.05 as we left the hotel, it started raining. Half hour more of deliberating and we thought sod it lets go. Even if it’s raining its what we have wanted to do the whole time we’ve been in Darjeeling (apart from the toy train of course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 29 – 35 Tuesday 12th to Monday 18th October – Darjeeling</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/19/days-29-35-tuesday-12th-to-monday-18th-october-darjeeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 16:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/19/days-29-35-tuesday-12th-to-monday-18th-october-darjeeling/</guid>
      <description>“A number of rewarding and picturesque treks are accessible from Darjeeling. October and November’s clear skies and warm temperatures make it an ideal time to trek…” says the Lonely Planet.
We wouldn’t know. For the past few days we have wanted to go on the Singalila trek where you can walk to a height of 3600m at Sandakphu and see the top of Everest clearly but the weather is beating us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt’s sparse update</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/17/matts-sparse-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 07:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/17/matts-sparse-update/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just found out that Karen’s Nan is being given print-outs of this blog, so a big hello to you from India!
After the first few days I was almost ready to just get on a plane back home again. The people were rude, and the city was filthy.
I’m over that initial culture-shock now (realising it was basically just Delhi) and am now really enjoying India. It’s a mad place, there’s no escaping that, but we’ve met some lovely people and already experienced a lifetime worth of bizarre events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 26 – 28 Saturday 9th to Monday 11th October – Varanasi</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/14/days-26-28-saturday-9th-to-monday-11th-october-varanasi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2010 16:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/14/days-26-28-saturday-9th-to-monday-11th-october-varanasi/</guid>
      <description>Varanasi has been our most surreal experience yet in India. More tuk-tuk touts than you can shake a stick at but a very spiritual and dream-like place.
Paul van der Werf from the train joined us and we made our way to Chaitanya Guest House in Assi Ghat which is the most southerly ghat in Varanasi and was very pleasant. There wasn’t the same amount of hustle and bustle here as in the old city which Varanasi is famous for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lack of photos</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/lack-of-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 16:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/lack-of-photos/</guid>
      <description>We will put more photos on our blog as soon as we get a quicker internet connection. Currently sat in our hotel room in Darjeeling and using the sim card for access and its so painfully slow I may cut off my right arm rather than wait any longer for the photos to upload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 25 – Friday 8th October – Delhi to Varanasi</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/day-25-friday-8th-october-delhi-to-varanasi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 15:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/day-25-friday-8th-october-delhi-to-varanasi/</guid>
      <description>Day 4 in Delhi
Off to Varanasi today so suddenly thought we ought to do some sightseeing. We chose the Lotus temple and it’s definitely worth seeing. An amazing bit of modern architecture which we think is almost as “wow” as the Taj Mahal. It looks like some kind of futuristic building set amongst green gardens and palm trees. It could be from a sci-fi film. Kind of reminded me of Logan’s run in a way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 24 Thursday 7th October – Delhi – CWG</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/day-24-thursday-7th-october-delhi-cwg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 15:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/day-24-thursday-7th-october-delhi-cwg/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 in Delhi – coincidences
Things improved today. Although we’re still in HUI. We bumped into two girls Abby and Beth (speech therapists from London) who were also off to see the athletics later. Coincidentally (i’m going to say that alot in these blogs) they were in the same block as us. So we travelled together to the stadium and watched the 100m mens and women’s finals.
The women’s was controversial because there was almost a false start because of the noise the crowd were making.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 23 Wednesday 6th October – Delhi – CWG</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/day-23-wednesday-6th-october-delhi-cwg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 15:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/day-23-wednesday-6th-october-delhi-cwg/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 in Delhi – The inefficiencies
We pop by Smyle Inn to ask about the room. Yes it will be ready later. Come back at noon. Ok so merrily we go off to get brekkie @ Sam’s Cafe. I won’t even go into that…
Back at 12 and the guy is oh i’m sorry we still have no room. do you mind staying at the other hotel another night? Um yes we do bloody mind mate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 22 Tuesday 5th October- Delhi – CWG</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/day-22-tuesday-5th-october-delhi-cwg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 15:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/day-22-tuesday-5th-october-delhi-cwg/</guid>
      <description>Our first experience of a sleeper train was pretty good. We’d booked far enough in advance to get the side upper and side lower beds in a 3AC carriage which meant we could sit opposite each other and go to bed whenever we wanted without worrying about anyone else.
It was an 18 hr journey but didn’t feel like it as from 21.30 til 7.30 we were pretty much sleeping. The evening was occupied with reading and interruptions of “chai, chai chai”, “coffee, nescafe, coffee” etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days 20-21 – Sunday 3rd &amp; Monday 4th October – Jaisalmer (Camel Trek)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/days-20-21-sunday-3rd-monday-4th-october-jaisalmer-camel-trek/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 13:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/13/days-20-21-sunday-3rd-monday-4th-october-jaisalmer-camel-trek/</guid>
      <description>I am writing this in retrospect and cannot believe it’s over a week since we did the camel trek. Time is flying by very fast.
Matt had a couple of days rest plus bought a course of antibiotics from the medical stall in the square for a quid and was ready to do the camel trek. We opted for a 1.5 day trek as we needed to get back by Monday afternoon for our trip to Delhi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17 – Thursday 30th September – Mt Abu to Jaisalmer (big rant)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/01/day-17-thursday-30th-september-mt-abu-to-jaisalmer-big-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 16:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/01/day-17-thursday-30th-september-mt-abu-to-jaisalmer-big-rant/</guid>
      <description>We arrived in Jaisalmer at 10pm. We left Mt Abu at 8am. 14 bloody hours it took to get here!
The Lonely Planet says there is a direct bus from Mt Abu to Jaisalmer which takes 11 hours. There isn’t.
The Lonely Planet says there are A/C buses available. There aren’t.
We sat on a hot sweaty bus for 7hrs to Jodphur. Bumping up and down and all over the place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16 – Wednesday 29th September – Mt Abu (Happy Birthday Dad!)</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/01/day-16-wednesday-29th-september-mt-abu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 16:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/10/01/day-16-wednesday-29th-september-mt-abu/</guid>
      <description>Firstly Happy Birthday to my dad! Sorry not there to see you. Hope you have a fab day and the card arrives in one piece without Rex chewing it up! x x x
 Mt Abu is unsurprisingly at the top of a mountain and the bus driver was a normal Indian driver – overtaking on bends and liking the edge of the road rather than the safer side. But we got here in one piece to another lake side town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 14 – Monday 27th September – Udaipur</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/27/day-14-27th-september-udaipur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 12:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/27/day-14-27th-september-udaipur/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday went for a gorgeous romantic meal at Ambrai restaurant overlooking Lake Pichola, Lake Palace Hotel on Jagniwas Island and City Palace. Beautiful setting. Lush food. Worth every penny. We normally spend around 300 rupees on a meal. That was 1000. Which works out about the same as a Dominos pizza!
Watched Octopussy in a lovely bar lazing on cushions on the floor. We recognised so much of the scenery. it was fun to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 12 – Saturday 25th September – Udaipur</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/27/day-12-saturday-25th-september-udaipur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 12:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/27/day-12-saturday-25th-september-udaipur/</guid>
      <description>We arrived in Udaipur late on 23rd and its not a bad substitute for Pushkar.
So far in Udaipur:-
cows blocking Daiji bridge- squealing chinese tourist!
bathing ghats and old naked washing women
rooftop sunsets
beautiful lake and palaces
good aubergine and tomato curry plus garlic cheese naan @ Jasmine restaurant by the bridge
Quirky Vintage &amp;amp; Classic Car collection with veg thali – personal viewings of the cars including black Rolls Royce rfom Octopussy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10 – Thursday 23rd September – Pushkar</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/27/day-10-thursday-23rd-september-pushkar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 12:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/27/day-10-thursday-23rd-september-pushkar/</guid>
      <description>Today we leave Pushkar to go to Udaipur but it’s a shame to go as we’re loving it here. Even though it is a veggie, alcohol-free place!
It’s a small town with winding streets full of market stalls surrounding a lake and itself surrounded by hills.
Now we have been here a few days people are recognising us so we’re not being hassled so much. Rather just lots of Namastes and they let us move on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8 – Tuesday 21st September – Pushkar</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/27/day-7-tuesday-21st-september-pushkar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 12:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/27/day-7-tuesday-21st-september-pushkar/</guid>
      <description>Matt has promised to add some photos soon to help make this blog more interesting! (he says see flickr :) )
Had enough of the bugs and electricity cuts and dirty walls in Hotel Sanjay so we’ve moved to a quieter part of town to Hotel Rising Star. Only 300 rupees a night (£4.20) and its so much cleaner and lovelier than being on Sadar Bazaar.
No views of the lake but we’re not that far away and in a cluster of other hotels recommended by LP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sayings</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/23/sayings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 05:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/23/sayings/</guid>
      <description>Here are a few sayings that are no longer as descriptive as they once were:
 Wait until the cows come home
Smaller than an ant
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7 – Monday 20th September – Pushkar</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/21/day-6-monday-20th-september-pushkar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 14:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/21/day-6-monday-20th-september-pushkar/</guid>
      <description>7am wakeup calls from the market traders and motorbikes in the street below didn’t deter us from the first lie-in in a while. Good old ear plugs. 11 o’clock we rolled into the Sadar Bazaar and mooched up the street looking for Laxmi market.
Accosted by Gutar in Navjyoti Tailors he successfully flogged us some new traveller styley clothes so we can start to blend in more. All Matt needs now is a tan and he’d look the part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6 – Sunday 19th September 2010 – Agra to Pushkar</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/20/day-6-sunday-19th-september-2010-agra-to-pushkar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 10:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/20/day-6-sunday-19th-september-2010-agra-to-pushkar/</guid>
      <description>Agra was a relief from Delhi as it wasn’t as hectic but it was very touristy and the tuk tuk drivers were there to get as much as poss out of you.
Except perhaps our last guy Ahmed who arrived at our door at 4am to take us to the train station for our 5.10 train to Ajmer.
This time we chose A/C Chair car so it was like being on a plane, not the comfiest to sleep in but we managed a few hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5 – Saturday 18th September 2010 – Agra – Taj Mahal &amp; Red Fort</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/20/day-5-saturday-18th-september-2010-agra-taj-mahal-red-fort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 10:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/20/day-5-saturday-18th-september-2010-agra-taj-mahal-red-fort/</guid>
      <description>6am outside Tourists Rest House, no sign of our lift. Not surprised as we weren’t interested in his all day tour of Agra for 600 rupees. We just wanted a lift to the Taj Mahal and play it by ear.
Found another keen soul who nicely ripped us off as he didn’t have any change. Then found out that he’d dropped us off at East Gate and the booking office was 1km away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 – friday 17th september 2010 – Delhi to Agra</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/20/day-4-friday-17th-september-2010-delhi-to-agra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 10:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/20/day-4-friday-17th-september-2010-delhi-to-agra/</guid>
      <description>Now in Agra after an epic journey. An hour in a tuk-tuk dodging traffic in Delhi, a manic New Delhi train station which was heaving with people who were sat/sprawled anywhere they could to shade out of the scorcher of a day.
We boarded the train at 13:35 – half an hour before it was scheduled to depart. Sat on a bottom bunk sleeper seat for a scheduled 3hr journey and arrived in Agra at 18:40 with 2 bags of a crisps as sustinence!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/16/day-3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 17:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/travels/2010/09/16/day-3-2/</guid>
      <description>Today is the third day since we arrived in Delhi.
This place is crazy. The roads are chaotic and you assume that there must be crashes every five minutes but somehow, everyone manages to weave in and out of each other as if controlled by some collective brain. Walking around the main parts of Delhi is pretty tiring. Touts constantly approach offering helpful directions to the official tourist office where you can book trains and trips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Update</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/07/01/challenge-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 14:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/07/01/challenge-update/</guid>
      <description>At the end of April I set myself the challenge of gaining a stone in weight and running a 5km race 2.5 minutes faster.
I ran the same race on Tuesday in 19:15, painfully close to my speed target of 19 minutes. However, I also weighed myself again but have actually lost a pound.
Gah!
Must try harder…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solved: How to rotate with GWTCanvas</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/07/01/how-to-rotate-with-gwtcanvas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 14:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/07/01/how-to-rotate-with-gwtcanvas/</guid>
      <description>Having trouble rotating something you’ve drawn with GWTCanvas?
It took me a little while to work out, but GWTCanvas works slightly differently to Graphic2D in Java. It’s important to realise that with GWTCanvas, when you invoke “rotate(r)” you’re actually transforming the coordinate space that will be used for subsequent drawing.
canvas.moveTo(50, 50); canvas.lineTo(50, 10); canvas.stroke();  Produces:
In order to rotate it, you must invoke rotate before you start any drawing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bristol Bike Rental scheme comes to an end…</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/05/12/bristol-bike-rental-scheme-comes-to-an-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 09:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/05/12/bristol-bike-rental-scheme-comes-to-an-end/</guid>
      <description>Bristol have been trialling a bike rental scheme for about a year and I had high hopes for it. I paid my £20 in support of the scheme even though there were no bike stations in the places I needed them. I feel if there were more bikes and more stations it would have been ideal. (see my comment from back then…).
Unfortunately, they’ve decided to end the scheme deeming it unsuccessful:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Challenge: 1.5 stone heavier and 2.5 minutes faster</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/04/28/the-challenge-15-stone-heavier-and-25-minutes-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 14:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/04/28/the-challenge-15-stone-heavier-and-25-minutes-faster/</guid>
      <description>Last night I ran a pretty shonky 21:33 (~7m/mile) for the Bridge Inn 5km. I used to be faster but haven’t really been running since last year.
I also need to put on some weight because at 6 foot I’m pretty puny weighing in at 10st 9lb. According to the NHS weight calculator I should be over 12 Stone.
I’m setting myself the challenge of knocking 2.5 minutes off my 5km time (I’ve never run it under 19 minutes before) and reaching 12st 2lb before the Bridge Inn 5km summer series finishes on July 27th (the website hints there’s one in August but I’m pretty sure it’s wrong…).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix the aspect ratio on videos from Windows Movie Maker Live</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/02/21/how-to-fix-the-aspect-ratio-on-videos-from-windows-movie-maker-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2010 20:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/02/21/how-to-fix-the-aspect-ratio-on-videos-from-windows-movie-maker-live/</guid>
      <description>Problem:
wmv file looks squashed when played in VLC or when uploaded to youtube but looks fine when played in windows media player
Solution:
You can change the aspect ratio of a wmv file without re-encoding it with vmarchanger
Ok, hopefully you just searched for this and you’re now sorted, but here’s some background on my problem in case it helps.
I made a small video (640×480 50fps) on my 7D and wanted to slap it on youtube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A build that’s green, should never be seen.</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/01/15/a-build-thats-green-should-never-be-seen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 23:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/01/15/a-build-thats-green-should-never-be-seen/</guid>
      <description>Your continuous integration server should stay green all the time. The odd broken test here and there means you get numb to the failed status on your build server, which in turn means it takes you longer to notice that the build has broken. When the build breaks, you should stop whatever you’re doing and make fixing it your top* priority. After you check in, the faster you fail the better because you haven’t had time to start thinking about your next task, and the thing you did to break the build is still fresh in your mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Company Locator</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/01/12/software-company-locator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 13:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2010/01/12/software-company-locator/</guid>
      <description>Looking software companies are near you? Looking to switch jobs or perhaps your company is looking for a local consultancy to collaborate on that big contract?
I helped Dan make this map as a quick way to find those companies:
Larger version.We’d love it if you could contribute updates. Just log in with your Google account and click the “edit” button on the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I buy a Canon 7D in the US and carry back to the UK?</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2009/11/09/should-i-buy-a-canon-7d-in-the-us-and-carry-back-to-the-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 16:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2009/11/09/should-i-buy-a-canon-7d-in-the-us-and-carry-back-to-the-uk/</guid>
      <description>Canon have just released the 7D and although I can’t really afford it, I have to have one!
The price difference between UK and US is pretty crazy. Here, my favourite camera shop are selling body only for £1,399. £300 less than Canon’s SRP. In New York’s B&amp;amp;H store you can pick it up for $1,699 (~£1,014).
As luck would have it, I’m going to NY this weekend so if I’m going to buy one, now’s the time to decide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The web in 3D!</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2009/04/01/the-web-in-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 15:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2009/04/01/the-web-in-3d/</guid>
      <description>Download Google Chrome 3D edition as created by CADIE.
But don’t forget to download and print your 3D glasses otherwise it’ll be all fuzzy:
You’d be a fool not to try it 🙂</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your filling knife clean</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2009/03/02/keep-your-filling-knife-clean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 22:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2009/03/02/keep-your-filling-knife-clean/</guid>
      <description>I’m no expert when it comes to DIY. Enthusiastic amateur I’d say.
I fumble my way along, guessing how things should be done, and generally learn the hard way.
I needed to do some more filling today to plug the holes I’d left from my poor skirting board fitting skills.
My filling knife however was caked in gunk after a few years of not being cleaned properly. I kept it clean when I first got it, it was new and I took good care of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voucher codes and promo wotsits</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2009/01/22/voucher-codes-and-promo-wotsits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 11:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2009/01/22/voucher-codes-and-promo-wotsits/</guid>
      <description>It’s 2009! Our digital lives are a breeze and online shopping is just one more option to the newly empowered consumer. Right?
I’m sure I’m not alone in finding the process of buying anything a little tedious now:
 See something in the shop you like Decide not to buy it because you don’t know if that’s a good price You get home and look on the internet Now you have to poke around a few websites and try to work out which is cheapest when you consider postage and tax etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Stalking</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2008/11/28/audio-stalking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 11:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2008/11/28/audio-stalking/</guid>
      <description>I’m just writting this as a holding place for funny things I overhear. Little bits of someone else’s conversation caught out of context. I hope this is just the beginning or a lifelong reel of quotes that I append to as funny things enter my ears from the mouths of unaware passers-by.
I’m starting it because I just heard:
 “How did it survive being cooked in a flapjack”
 I have no idea what she was talking about, and to be honest, I don’t want to know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mattburns co uk</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/ignore-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 11:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/ignore-index/</guid>
      <description>home
this is all there is</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing the volume up key on a nokia N95</title>
      <link>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2008/11/19/fixing-the-volume-up-key-on-a-nokia-n95/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 23:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mattburns.co.uk/blog/2008/11/19/fixing-the-volume-up-key-on-a-nokia-n95/</guid>
      <description>I recently got my hands on a nokia N95. Great.
However, I soon realised that the volume up key doesn’t work, only down works. This was a little unfortunate since it is the only key capable of turning the volume up of music when played with the music player software installed on the device. Something I definitely needed to do once I had managed to turn the volume down to zero percent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
